[Slinky clanking]
I love money.
I love money more
Than i love
the things it can buy.
Does that surprise you?
Money. It don't care
whether i'm good or not.
It don't care whether
i snore or not.
It don't care
which god i pray to.
There are only three things
in this world
With that kind of
unconditional acceptance--
Dogs...
Doughnuts...
And money.
Only money is better.
You know why?
Because it don't
make you fat
And it don't poop all over
the living room floor.
There's only one thing
i like better...
Other people's money.
All right, now,
squeeze in over here.
I want to see
all your faces.
Now face the camera.
Get up on the floor, sir.
Happy thanksgiving!
How you doing, tom?
Happy thanksgiving, jorgy!
Happy thanksgiving,
everybody!
Happy thanksgiving.
Man: smile, everybody!
Take a good one, elton.
The stock is up another
point and a half!
Somebody's
up to something, jorgy.
Good news. Stock is up.
Don't worry about it.
Gus, you got
your teeth in?
Ready now!
Cheeks up!
New england
wire and cable!
New england wire and cable!
Yes! All right!
[Beep]
Up two points.
Wire and cable,
[Television plays]
* up two points,
up two points *
* wire and cable,
* up two points *
up two points *
* up two points,
* wire and cable,
up two points *
* up two points,
* wire and cable *
up two points **
Morning, mr. Garfield.
Morning, arthur.
Say good morning
to carmen.
She's very happy today.
Aren't you, my sweet?
Good morning, carmen.
Cranberry juice is
fresh today, boss.
Oh, good.
You never let me down,
arthur.
You never let me down.
[Car horn honks loudly]
Good morning, sir.
Samuels.
Both:
good morning, mr. Garfield.
[Grunts]
Good morning,
mr. Garfield.
Good morning.
Morning.
Good morning,
mr. Garfield.
Morning.
Good morning,
mr. Garfield.
Work, work!
Good morning,
mr. Garfield.
Good morning.
Good morning,
mr. Garfield.
Yeah!
Good morning, mr. Garfield.
You look very nice today.
I'm not paying you
to be polite, harriet.
What's happening?
Good morning, mr. Garfield.
Morning.
Mr. Holt wants to see you
for dinner if you can,
And the overly brothers
Will fly you to texas
or they'll come here--
Whichever you want.
When i die, harriet,
put on my gravestone--
"He never
went to texas."
Yes, sir.
I'll call the engraver.
Where's the cinnamon?
Out of cinnamon.
If i can't count
on dunkin' donuts,
Who do i count on?
Well, you can count
on me, sir.
Heh! Granger.
Trundel canning.
Tell me.
Trundel's being sued
by the townspeople, sir.
Failed to comply with
environmental restrictions.
Hmm...
And there are claims
of illness
From the citizenry.
Good.
Just before they're
carted off to jail,
Make a bid.
Yes, sir.
Angeli.
Yo?
Eastern motels.
Outstanding shares?
Uh...6 million,
mr. Garfield.
Slate
owns 2 1/2 million.
Mr. Morganstern
wants to talk to you.
I'd rather talk
to my mother.
Pfeiffer!
Yeah?
What about
this new england
Wire and cable?
It's too beautiful.
Is it booby-Trapped?
I, uh...
I...
Can't seem to find
any problems...
Mr. Garfield.
Neither can i.
Richardson?
Yes, sir.
Let's talk
to these people.
Call the man in charge,
whoever the hell he is.
Yes, sir.
We'll get right on it.
[Telephone rings]
[Ring]
New england
wire and cable.
Good morning.
The general manager,
please.
That'd be mr. Coles.
Who shall i say
is calling?
Lawrence garfield.
Just one moment,
please.
What'd he want?
To come up and see us.
Look the place over,
he said.
What's wrong with that?
He's a shareholder.
It's not that simple.
What this man does
is no secret.
Bill, you got the jitters.
Wall street's in the
liquidation business
These days, jorgy.
My father founded
this company 81 years ago.
I took over 26 years ago.
I control this company,
And nobody's going
to liquidate us.
What a shit pit.
Ohh...look at this.
Look at this.
I haven't seen a place
this classy
Since i left the bronx.
Welcome to new england
wire and cable.
I'm bea sullivan,
Mr. Jorgenson's
assistant.
How do you do?
I do good.
Would you like to
invite your chauffeur in
To keep warm?
He's a yard
chauffeur, honey.
Bring him inside,
you spoil him.
Is there
a dunkin' donuts
In this town?
Dunkin' donuts?
No, i don't think so.
Crispy cremes,
something?
I'm afraid not.
But we have coffee,
And emma might have
a breakfast roll.
A breakfast roll?
Do you have an elevator?
I'm embarrassed to tell you
it's out of order.
You know elevators.
Any oxygen?
[Panting]
Should have warned me,
I'd have brought
a paramedic.
Is it much further?
I'd like to get there
before dark.
Jorgy,
this is mr. Garfield.
Mr. Garfield,
Andrew jorgenson,
our chairman.
Call me jorgy.
Everybody else does.
Sorry about the elevator.
It has a mind of its own.
Mr. Coles, our president
and general manager.
Emma,
bring in the coffee!
Last limousine
we saw here was in '48
When harry truman was
running for president.
That's right.
He stood right out there
On those stairs
exactly where you were.
Is that so?
Yep.
That was the golden age.
Rebuilding america
and all that.
Old harry made
a great speech that day.
Is that so?
Oh, yes. He was
very impressive.
He's the only democrat
bea and i ever voted for.
Do you know much about
the wire and cable business?
I know if the cable's
out of whack,
The elevator don't go up.
I'm thinking about
the doughnuts.
Doughnuts?
Mr. Garfield was
wondering if we had any.
Uh, bill,
do we have doughnuts?
I don't think so.
How's that coffee
coming along?
Here we are,
mr. Garfield.
Thank you.
Sugar and cream?
Sugar.
I'll take care of it.
Thank you, emma.
I could have emma
get some doughnuts.
No, no. Why don't we
get down to business?
What's the matter?
You're not interested
in doughnuts?
Would you like me
to get some doughnuts?
Jorgenson:
no. Never mind, emma.
You're right.
Let's talk business.
Good idea. What business
are we talking about?
Good coffee.
Well, let's put it
this way.
Back in new york,
i got a computer.
Her name is carmen.
Every morning, right
after i brush my teeth,
I punch out, "carmen,
computer on the wall,
Who's the fairest
of them all?"
Now, most mornings
she spits out,
"Garfield,
you're the fairest."
But three weeks ago,
she said,
"Garfield, garfield,
scratch your balls.
"New england"--Pardon me--
"New england wire and cable
is the fairest of them all."
New england
wire and cable?
I said, "what's it worth?"
So she showed me
the numbers.
You got equipment here
that cost $120 million.
Even at salvage,
It's worth 30,
35 million.
Can i use that blackboard
over there?
Yeah, go ahead.
Thank you.
Come with me.
Carmen will educate us.
Going to erase
this stuff here.
Here.
Let's--Let's put down
30 million.
How many
acres you got?
110.
Carmen and i figure
even as farmland,
Grazing land,
it's worth 10 million.
Is that fair?
Yeah.
Let's lay the 10
under the 30.
That makes 40 million.
All right.
And you bought
some other companies,
Didn't you, bill?
You have a plumbing,
an electrical,
And some kind
of adhesive company.
Boring, but all
making a decent profit.
Carmen says they're
worth another 60 mil.
Let's put the 60
under the 40.
And you have working
capital of 25 million,
10 0f it in cash.
Let's put down
25 million, add them up,
And see what you got.
$125 million.
The only bad news is
That this wire
and cable division
Isn't making
a profit.
And all
the other divisions
Have to support you.
Now,
as a stockholder,
That doesn't
make me very happy.
Are you finished,
mr. Garfield?
No, i'm not, bill.
Let's say carmen
was suffering
From premenstrual
syndrome.
No offense.
A little nuts.
Let's say she was
too optimistic.
Let's knock off
25 million.
Here we go.
Let's make it...
$100 million.
A nice round number.
I like nice
round numbers.
Any debt? No.
Any lawsuits?
Any environmental
bullshit?
You throwing garbage
in the water?
Of course not.
Not you.
What about pension
liabilities?
Carmen says
you're fully funded.
You people
are dreams.
I think
this meeting is over.
No, no, no, wait a minute.
Wait a minute.
Here comes the fun part.
How many shares
outstanding you got?
4 million.
Divide 4 million
into 100 million,
What do you get?
25.
Good. That means each
share is worth $25.
But that
was all foreplay.
Let's go
for the real thing.
The stock was 10
When i woke up
3 weeks ago.
That's a 10
for a $25-Item.
What a sale.
Something worth $25,
i can buy it for 10.
The company's not
for sale, mr. Garfield.
I don't want your company,
jorgy.
I just want what every
other stockholder wants--
I want to make money.
You are
making money.
You bought the stock
at 10. It's now 14.
The stock is 14
because i'm buying it.
I'm doing my part,
now you do yours.
Get rid of this
wire and cable division.
It's a financial cancer.
Would you excuse us,
please?
I want to talk
to mr. Garfield alone.
What the hell do you
think you're doing,
You little son
of a bitch?
You can't come
into my town,
My plant,
take my company.
You can't do that.
You been livin'
on mars, jorgy?
It's called
a corporate takeover.
I know
what it's called,
And i'm not going
to let you do it.
It's simple.
I do it all the time.
Well, do it
someplace else.
I'm not going
to commit suicide.
Don't think of it
as suicide. Yecchh.
Think of it
as euthanasia.
Get out. Get out.
Get out before
i throw you out.
Where are you going?
We're just
doing business.
Business? With you?
[Chuckling]
I got a company to run.
Yeah, well,
that's my point.
I don't like the way
my company's being run!
And you better get
your elevator fixed!
There's a goddamn
fire raging here,
And this whole industry's
up in flames!
And you call
the fire department,
And who shows up? Nobody.
Because they're all
in japan and singapore
And malaysia and taiwan
and every other shit hole
Where they're crazy
about pollution.
And while
that inferno is raging,
You're out in front
mowing the lawn, tidying up,
Playing with your putz
on my money!
You'd think i was
asking him for a loan.
Good day, mr. Garfield.
I'm not
a long-Term player.
[Horn honks]
They give us
trouble today?
They're not
going to send us
Back to the bronx,
arthur.
Don't scare me, there,
mr. G.
Richardson,
i want to buy up
New england wire
and cable.
Buy everything
you can.
File a goddamned
13-D.
I want to finish
this one quick.
Richardson:
we're on it.
Well, it's official.
Our friend
garfield's intent
Is to take
over the company.
He's filed his 13-D
With the s.E.C.
He now owns
12% of us.
What do you want
to do?
I own 20%.
Jorgy, we've got
to protect ourselves.
We need legal advice.
We have lawyers.
They're not equipped
to handle this.
We need the best.
We want
to call kate.
Let me.
What makes you think
she'll come?
I'll tell her
we need her.
We're family.
Flamboyant ls and ms.
Loves to write
million, doesn't he?
We've never seen
a man like that.
He's like something
out of a comic book.
So they say.
Hello, kate.
Jorgy.
Thanks for coming.
Doesn't she
look splendid?
I have to be back
in the city by 5:00.
Would you mind if we
get right down to it?
You're
in charge, kate.
Now, given that
someone's interested
In moving in on you,
You've no choice but
to protect yourself.
You have some options.
For openers,
i recommend changing
Your state
of incorporation
From rhode island
to delaware.
Why delaware?
That's a good idea.
Strong anti-Takeover
legislation there.
That way we're not
playing dead.
Who the hell is
playing dead?
You have
to protect yourself.
By running away
to delaware?
It's only on paper.
This company was
founded in rhode island.
It will remain
in rhode island.
I'm talking
about delaware,
Not nairobi.
Come on.
I own 20% of this company.
The board owns another 5,
The employees another 5%.
That's 30%.
Now how can this man
get control?
What do you want,
For me to negotiate
a deal or not?
But there's no deal
to be made.
He's knocking
at your door.
If you don't
answer it,
It's the same as
inviting him in.
Listen to her, jorgy.
There's no deal
to be made with predators.
You kill it
or it kills you.
Well,
what do you suggest?
Make it worth
his while to leave.
How? How?
What do you mean?
Pay him off.
Buy him out at a profit.
It's greenmail, jorgy,
But it's done
all the time.
It's terrorism,
and i won't do it!
Any other options?
You're going to lose
your company.
Like hell i am.
You, as they say
in the street,
Are in play.
Garfield
put you there,
And now i'm here
as your lawyer.
Isn't that a hell
of an irony?
Me trying to save
your company.
Well, i can do it.
[Intercom buzzes]
Yeah?
A miss sullivan
From hudson, bradley,
and flint is here.
And granger wants to
discuss trundel canning,
And your suits
are ready for a fitting.
Can they come up
at 5:00?
Tell 'em 5:00 is ok.
But tell 'em
not to send
The blind
son of a bitch
With the pins.
And tell granger if
he wants to see me
He'd better make
sense this time
Or he can get on the
unemployment line.
Shall i use those
exact words, sir?
Send in hudson,
bradley, and flint.
Whew.
Wow.
Whew!
You know what kills me?
I've done maybe 7, 8
deals like this before,
And you know
who i negotiate with?
Skinny little joggers
with contact lenses
All stinking from
the same aftershave.
I'm kate sullivan.
I know your name.
Want a cigarette?
No, thank you.
Don't let me stop you.
Why would you
stop me?
What are you,
a fucking lawyer?
Depends on who i'm with.
Welcome to my life.
So, what's it
going to be?
Sue, settle, defend?
I came to talk.
Boof!
Oh, that's trouble.
Lawyers
want to talk--
Nothing but trouble.
How about
a doughnut?
No, thanks.
Why, are you
a health food freak?
No. Just not hungry.
You have to be hungry
to eat a doughnut?
You don't?
What, are you
shitting me?
All my life i never
heard such a thing.
Have to be hungry.
Why?
It don't taste
better that way.
How would you know?
What do you want?
I need a month.
Get lost.
I just got involved.
I need time
To get everybody's
act together.
My act is together.
If you give me
some time,
I think we can work
something out.
Settle?
Work something out.
I only settle
when i'm in trouble.
Or when it makes sense.
It only makes sense
when i'm in trouble.
Well, if you prefer,
we'll go to court.
Get an injunction,
have a fight.
All kinds
of allegations.
Costs them, costs you,
and for what?
I live in court.
You got to do
better than that.
I won't love you anymore.
Two weeks.
Standstill agreement.
Both sides.
No more buying.
Two weeks.
Thank you.
Whoa, whoa!
Where are you going?
We haven't talked about
what i want to talk about.
What's that?
You and me sweatin'
between satin sheets.
Garfield,
Put your hand
between your legs.
Do it!
Good.
Look directly down
at that little guy,
And you say, "you
must behave yourself
When you're in the
presence of a lady."
Garfield, you don't say
exactly that right now
I'm resigning
from this case.
You must behave
yourself...
You must
behave yourself...
When you're
in the presence...
in the presence
Of a lady.
See? Not so hard.
[Buzz]
See you
in two weeks.
Wow! Did you
see that, carmen?
I love it, love it,
love it.
Goodbye,
miss sullivan.
Goodbye.
[Buzz]
Call erickson, tell him
to arrange some money
Through the royal bank.
Don't pay him more than
we did on fleetwood.
Then call hathaway,
tell him
I want
to make a tender offer
For new england
wire and cable.
Don't put it under our name.
Label it "opm holdings."
But what if she finds out
we broke the agreement?
Richardson, were
you born yesterday?
What do you think
she's doing as we speak?
That kewpie doll's up
to no good. Do it.
I got us
an extra two weeks.
Now we have to move fast.
Get the board to buy up
as many shares as they can.
Use your own
working capital.
Andrew: no, no, that's not
what those dollars are for.
That's our safety net.
Then borrow the money.
No borrowing.
Andrew, listen to her.
She's making sense.
For every share
you acquire,
It's one less
for garfield.
The more we buy,
the less for him.
The more it costs,
the less profit he makes.
So get the stock up.
Oh, and mom,
make sure to buy it through
An out-Of-State broker.
I don't want
to borrow money.
We've been debt-Free
since the depression.
But see,
that's the trouble.
It's your gorgeous
balance sheet
That makes
you so attractive.
Oh, and mom, get letters
out to the shareholders.
Tell them
how great business is,
And how wonderful
the future looks.
I'll do it.
Great. I'll call you
tomorrow. Good night.
Mmm.
Mmm...
good morning, honey.
How you doing
this morning, huh?
Oh...
Ooh...
You got it up again.
Another point
and a half.
Pfeiffer.
Good morning,
mr. Garfield.
Woody.
Good morning.
Harriet.
Miss sullivan is gonna
call tomorrow morning.
You tell her
i'm not taking calls.
Then when she comes
over here
And tries to storm
into the office,
You try to keep her out.
But then you can
let her push past.
Don't worry, she's
desperate but harmless.
Find out where she lives
and call the florist.
Florist?
Florist.
You have a good evening,
miss sullivan.
Hello, michael.
Oh, miss sullivan. Uh...
Here. Somebody
brought these by for you.
Oh, thank you.
Good night.
Good morning.
Oh! You ruthless
son of a bitch!
Excuse me?
Jeez, what's
her problem?
Uhh!
All right,
all right.
Sorry to get
in your way.
May i help you?
I'm afraid
mr. Garfield isn't in.
I don't care!
It's all right, harriet.
No, it's not all right,
you hypocrite! You lied!
Oh. But babypoo--
We had an agreement.
We had a standstill!
No more buying!
You know nothing
about opm holdings?
Opm?
Not much to know.
You broke the agreement!
You embarrassed me
with my firm
And with my clients!
Wait a minute.
Don't come on
so holier-Than-Thou with me.
What am i supposed to do,
sit her and twiddle my thumbs
While you drive up
the price of the stock?
I did no such thing.
You're full of shit.
All that buying coming
from some little firm
In rhode island?
You'd think you'd use
an out-Of-State firm.
I know nothing
about that.
Give me a break.
Who am dealing with
here, mother teresa?
You want
to play the game,
Learn to play it right.
Oh, is that what you
call it, a game?
You're damn right.
The best game
in the world.
I'll teach you.
It's easy.
You make
as much as you can
For as long
as you can.
And then what?
"And then what?"
Whoever has the most
when he dies, wins.
Look. It's
the american way.
I'm doing my job.
I'm a capitalist.
I'm simply
following the law
Of free enterprise.
What law is that?
Survival
of the fittest.
Well, maybe some people
don't see it that way.
Maybe they don't see it
as survival of the fittest.
Maybe they see it
as survival of the fattest!
Oh, katie, why are
you so hard on me?
'Cause you're not nice.
Since when do you have
to be nice to be right?
You're not right.
You're what's happening.
One day we'll smarten up
and pass some laws
And put you
out of business.
They can pass
all the laws they want.
All they can do
is change the rules.
They can never
stop the game.
I don't go away.
I adapt.
10 years from now,
they'll be studying you
At the wharton school.
They'll call it
"the garfield era"
And rinse their mouths out
when they leave the room!
I'll see you in court!
Oh, katie,
don't leave.
We haven't talked
about sex yet.
At least have
a doughnut.
Stuff it!
Don't be a poor loser!
Lying to protect
your client
Is just doing a good job!
I understand that!
You didn't even ask me
what opm stands for!
Other people's money!
All right,
come on, come on!
Get--Let's go!
Work, work, work!
Yes, sir!
Gotcha!
Oh, yes!
How do you have 'em?
Two years ago,
He tried to take over
westridge corporation.
He was put
under indictment
For not disclosing
his 13-D. What's this?
Your christmas list.
What'd they do to him?
Nothing. The government
dropped the charges.
Nope.
Investors get hurt?
If the charges were dropped,
it's a technicality.
He was required
to disclose.
Gerber's in
prison, richard.
Judge pollard
ain't going to give you
A restraining order
based on a technicality.
We are a nation
of laws, marcia.
Ultimately,
Those laws come down
to technicalities.
Without those
technicalities,
What do we have?
Anarchy.
Garfield.
Anarchy?
That's the basis
for your brief?
Correct.
Honeybunch, you better
write a fantastic brief.
I intend to.
Want to send anything
to garfield?
Yeah. A court order.
Oh, do the japanese
celebrate christmas?
No, but i hear
they're buying it.
Oh...
I had nothing to do
with any of this!
Pfeiffer comes--
Shh!
T.R.O.
Temporary
restraining order.
Thank you very much.
Some crew i've got.
17 lawyers on retainer,
And you manage
to work it out
So that in a free market,
A so-Called
free country,
I can't buy
some shit-Ass stock
Every other asshole
can buy.
Congratulations.
You're destroying
the capitalist system.
While everybody else in
the world is embracing it,
My boys and girls
are fucking it up!
You know what happens
When capitalism
gets fucked up?
The communists come back.
They come
out of the bushes.
Don't kid yourself.
They're waiting in there.
But maybe
that's not so bad.
Because you know
what happens
When the commies
take over?
The first thing they do
Is shoot all the lawyers!
And if they miss
any of you,
I'll do it myself!
Now let's see if we can get
this small-Town judge
To change
his fucking mind!
Come on!
It wasn't me! I was
in san francisco!
It was pfeiffer!
[Shouting]
[Beep]
Mr. Garfield,
A miss sullivan
is on the line.
Yes.
Hello, lawrence.
We're here in the office
Toasting
judge pollard's decision.
Stop gloating.
It doesn't become you.
Don't be a poor loser.
I got you
on a technicality.
Not bad for some broad
wet behind the ears.
I'd like to talk.
I've no time for talk.
My days are full.
I'll buy you a doughnut.
I'm not hungry.
Since when do you
have to be hungry
To have a doughnut?
Aw, shut up.
Stop pouting.
I'll buy you dinner.
Name the place.
I have
a proposition for you.
You're trying
to seduce me.
Heh heh heh heh heh.
You have a nice laugh.
My house, 8:00.
How about lutece?
I want to talk
to somebody,
I go to them.
You want to talk,
come to me. 8:00.
I'll come for 20 minutes.
That's all i need.
Strictly business.
20 minutes,
my place, 8:00.
5:30.
5:30? Funerals
are at 5:30.
7:00.
6:00.
I got to wash my face.
6:30.
Deal.
Harriet!
Get me my barber.
Get me my manicurist.
Call arthur.
She's coming to the house.
[Doorbell chimes]
Ah, miss sullivan.
That's me.
Come on in.
The boss is expecting ya.
Thank you.
Mr. G'll be
right with ya.
Thank you.
Gloria taylor.
Quarterback's girlfriend.
All that putz wanted
to do
Was take her pants off
in the back seat,
While i was ready
to feed her,
Protect her, put jewels
around her neck.
I sent her poetry.
Longfellow.
Can't go wrong
with longfellow.
"Day by day,
i gazed upon her.
"I sighed with passion.
"Day by day,
my heart within me
Grew more hot
with love and longing."
I gave her hiawatha.
All she wanted
was a touchdown.
Yeah...
To the quarterback's
girlfriend.
To gloria.
Drink, drink.
It's the best.
You look terrific.
Thank you.
How about
some mushroom dip?
I thought this was
a business meeting.
What's wrong
with a little dip?
I never met a person
so hard to feed.
Who are you mad at?
Come on, have some dip.
Swallow.
Mmm. Nice.
I think we should
talk business.
You have
an exquisite neck.
I have to leave
by 7:00.
I have
another engagement.
Oh, right. I forgot.
You got a proposition.
Thank you.
Ahh...
Shoot.
What will it take
for you to go away?
Greenmail? You're
offering to buy me out?
Why so uptight?
It's not illegal.
It's immoral.
A distinction
That has no relevance
for lawyers,
But it matters to me.
Well, for someone
who has nothing nice
To say about lawyers,
You certainly have
plenty of them around.
They're like
nuclear warheads.
They have theirs,
so i have mine.
Once you use them,
they fuck up everything.
Let me ask you.
Do you have authorization
to offer me greenmail?
Of course not.
It's a lawyer's scheme.
Everybody
walks out happy.
I get paid off.
Jorgy keeps his company.
The employees
keep their yobs.
The lawyer
gets a big fat fee.
Everybody walks out.
Yumpin' yiminy.
Sounds
pretty good to me.
Except
for the stockholders.
Their stock
falls out of bed,
They don't know
what hit 'em.
Now you're
albert schweitzer.
No, not albert schweitzer,
robin hood.
I take from the rich
and i give to the middle class.
Well, the upper middle class.
Would you care for some caviar?
The stock is 18.
Do you like music?
Do you like the violin?
Let's be serious.
Come on, let's change
the subject.
Arthur!
The stock is 18.
We'll buy it back at 18.
First you laugh at me,
then you insult me.
Then name your number.
What will you take?
25.
The stock hasn't seen 25
in years.
You want history?
The stock was once 60.
Take 20.
Such a high achiever.
If you're mad
at somebody,
Don't take it
out on me.
25 is my number,
and that's a favor.
Well, i don't like
your number,
And i don't need
to be analyzed.
Do we have a deal
or not?
Let's discuss it
over dinner.
Good night.
Your 20 minutes are up.
Wait a minute.
I want us to be friends.
Let's segue into some
soup and french bread.
Come on.
Don't go away mad.
I didn't buy
your proposition.
Come back
with another one.
You're an emancipated
woman. Learn to lose.
I haven't lost.
Wait, wait! I've got
a proposition for you.
Hold on,
you got to listen.
You come on back up.
We have a nice dinner.
We make passionate love
the rest of the night.
The first one
who comes, loses.
Loses what?
The deal.
I come first,
I sell you back
my shares at cost.
You come first,
you buy 'em at 25.
I think you're serious.
So how do you suggest
we write this up?
Delicately.
Under the heading,
"easy come, easy go."
Come on, what do you got
to lose, your virginity?
I could lose millions.
So what happens
if we come together?
I never thought of that.
Well, think
about it, honey.
I will. I will.
Wait a minute.
Come on. Don't go.
I haven't played
my violin yet.
Yeah.
[Thunder]
While the banks are
hemming and hawing
As customers
borrow money--
Mmm...
[Telephone rings]
[Ring]
Oh, god.
Hello?
I just want to see
if you got home safe.
Thank you.
In your beddie-Bye?
I am.
Did i wake you?
No.
Heh heh.
Did you have dinner?
Yes.
With who?
None of your business.
Ha ha.
Are you thinking
about me?
No.
Well, how could you
possibly manage that?
Oh, uh...pills, whiskey,
self-Help tapes.
Ha ha ha.
Ha ha ha ha ha.
Aah...
I got another
proposition for you.
Oh, yeah.
I can't wait.
We swap.
Swap what, dirty jokes?
Ha ha.
No. I give you
all my shares.
You give me the wire
and cable division.
Hello?
Hello? You like?
I'll ask them.
Good.
All right, now wait.
Don't go away.
Don't hang up.
Stay right where
you are. All right.
Ok.
[Violin plays
i'm in the mood for love]
[Humming]
Ha ha ha ha.
Here comes the bridge.
* why stop
to think of whether *
* this little dream
might fade? *
* let's put
our hearts together *
* now we are one *
* i'm not afraid *
[Humming]
Ha ha ha ha.
* la-La la-La
la la-La *
* but for
the night forget it *
* i'm in the mood
for love **
Huh?
Ha ha.
That was very good.
Thank you.
You're welcome.
That was just for you.
Well, i appreciate it.
Sweet dreams.
Ok. Good night.
Bye-Bye.
Oh, god.
Oohhh...
Oh.
[Giggling]
* i'm in the mood
for love **
Forget it.
Tell him
to go to hell.
He spends $13 million
for this place,
Then he sells it
for 35,
My guys are out
of work,
And he's made
$22 million.
Now how do i live
with that?
We eliminate
a losing division.
The other divisions
Don't have to
support us anymore.
I don't want
to hear that.
But you still control
the company,
You just don't have
the cable division.
Why is it so difficult
For everybody to understand
Why i can't kill
these people and this town
To enrich
some son of a bitch
Who's trying
to destroy me?
I can't play with him
in the courts forever.
He'll get
the injunction lifted
And buy more shares.
Don't be
a pig-Headed fool!
He deserves
to lose this company.
Good night,
mr. Jorgenson.
Oh, good night,
gus.
Everything going along
ok, mr. Jorgenson?
Everything's moving
right along, gus.
Everything's going to be
ok, isn't it?
At the plant, i mean,
the plant and everything.
Everything's going to be
just fine.
We'll be making
wire and cable
For a long time.
Yes, sir.
Good night, sir.
Good night.
Jorgy?
Have you got a minute?
Sure, bill.
Do you mind if i speak
frankly to you, jorgy?
You always have,
haven't you?
You know...
i'm trained to think
In contingency.
You know
i've spent my life
Managing businesses,
and, uh...
And...
Bill, you're
in a panic.
Well, you know how it is
with business, jorgy.
When things don't
work out quite right
And people have invested
a lot of their time,
A lot of their energy,
a lot of themselves.
Management
takes care of its own.
It happens all the time.
And given
the uncertainty
Surrounding us
these days
And...the fact that
you haven't set up
Any financial guarantees
for us, jorgy...
Oh, lord, i hate--
Hate giving this speech.
When i retire
in two years,
I've told you you're
taking over the business.
I promised you that.
There won't be
any business
In two years, jorgy.
There won't be
any business
In one year.
You're holding
onto a dream.
Go home, bill.
Have a drink.
Give my best
to jeanette.
I don't want the rug
pulled out from under me
So close
to the finish line.
Good night.
Jorgy, i've been here
15 years.
I have a family.
Something's due me.
Now, i've worked
my ass off for 15 years,
And you're going
to let that man come in
And take over the
company. It's not right.
I'm sorry, bill.
Up here we don't
plan the funeral
Until the body is dead.
[Talking and shouting]
Sounds like
everybody's hungry.
Well, let's eat.
Sit down, darling.
Happy thanksgiving.
Happy
thanksgiving.
[Ting ting]
Thank thee, father,
for thy care,
For thy bounty everywhere.
For this
and every other gift,
Our grateful hearts
to thee we lift. Amen.
2nd down and 10.
Lions at their 49.
I don't know why
you watch this.
It's so stupid.
If you watch,
you'll see.
Yes! Go! Go! Go!
I told you. My money
was on detroit.
You have to admit
We still have fresh air
up here.
Feels good, all right.
I'm awfully glad
you came, kate.
It means a hell of a lot
to your mother.
I love your mother.
I can't say
i'm sorry for that,
But i am sorry
for whatever it is
It's done to you
in the last 21-Odd years.
I'm ok, jorgy.
Good. Now let's talk
a little business.
Let's quit talking
about what i won't do.
Let's talk about
what i will do.
I have a problem.
I'm a good lawyer.
I'm a lousy mind reader.
I want to put it
to a vote.
Annual meeting
in four weeks.
Want to put it in the hands
of the stockholders.
Can't do that.
It's too risky.
We could lose
everything.
You're a fighter.
I'm a fighter.
It's too dangerous.
There's no other choice
that i can live with.
This 30%,
this faithful 30%.
Can you absolutely
count on them?
They haven't let me down
so far.
Awful lot of ozzies
on our side.
Don't trust ozzie.
He's a banker.
I have to trust
my friends, kate.
This is going
to be tough.
I have to get garfield
to buy this.
He won't want to.
It's not
to his advantage.
Talk nice.
Give him
your best smile.
Come on, kate.
Let's take on
the little son of a bitch.
Let's kick his ass
All the way back
to wall street.
Yeah.
It's a quiet place.
I thought it would be
a good idea
If we calmed down a bit.
Do you like japanese?
I'd like to have sony.
Could you bring me
a knife and fork, please?
Hai.
So, what do you say?
A proxy fight?
I--I'd have to be nuts.
I could just sit
on my ass
And wait for the injunction
to lift,
Buy all the shares i need.
Anybody else,
i wouldn't even come to lunch.
You look very nice today.
But if you win,
lawrence,
It speeds up
the process.
You get what you want
in three months
Instead of a year,
maybe two.
I love it
when you call me lawrence.
Say it again.
There's a lot can stand
in your way, lawrence.
Anti-Takeover legislation's
in the works.
Drexel's gone under.
Milken's in jail.
Trump's waiting tables.
Don't threaten me.
And just maybe
you're overleveraged
And you can't afford
to wait.
Thank you.
You got any bread?
No bread.
They got no bread.
They want to
run the world,
They got no bread.
In three weeks, you
present your own slate.
If you win, you
buy everybody out at 20.
If you lose,
You sell us back
your shares at 15.
Worst case scenario--
You still make
a couple million.
Amazing people,
the japanese.
We blow the hell
out of them.
They go back to school,
learn english,
And start
to run the world.
What do we do?
We get big-Headed,
Start living
the good life,
Forget about schools.
People can't read.
People can't write.
Country's full of dropouts.
Education.
Who needs education
As long as you can
blow up the world?
Meanwhile, i got
everybody in my office
Learning japanese.
I've never seen
such a beautiful lawyer.
Come on, lawrence.
This is your game.
Winner takes all.
Rumor has it
you got balls.
I been trying
to show you for weeks.
Well, here's
your opportunity.
All right.
I can always use
a good proxy blood bath.
After all, i want to
give you a fighting chance.
I love ya.
Of course you do...
Because we're the same.
We are not the same,
lawrence.
Now, don't go
spreading that around.
You know what makes us
the same,
What sets us apart?
We care more
about the game
Than we do the players.
Oh, is that so?
Yeah...that's so.
I'm going to nail you,
lawrence,
And everybody
on wall street's
Gonna know how
some broad did you in.
Ooh...
You're so perfect for me.
I have to go.
Don't go.
Lunch is on me,
babypoo.
Where you going?
I have to go back
to the office.
Don't go back
Come and work for me.
[Speaking japanese]
Lady said to say
we have no doughnuts.
[Speaking japanese]
Here's your coffee,
boss.
You make me feel
like a "doity" crook.
Sneaking off to jersey
is not my style.
Can we speak frankly?
No. Lie to me.
Tell me how thrilled
you are to know me.
I always
speak frankly.
I hate people who say,
"can we speak frankly?"
It means they're bullshitting
me the rest of the time.
I'm listening.
Now...as you know,
i had 60,000 shares
Of new england stock
when we first met.
What am i getting,
a history lesson here?
Get to the point.
Since...
Becoming aware
of your...investments,
I bought an additional
40,000 shares.
I now have
100,000 shares.
Congratulations.
I'm prepared...
To sell you the right...
To vote those shares
at the annual meeting.
How much?
A million.
Too much.
You need a million shares
More than
you already own.
Now i can get you 10%
of the way there
In one transaction.
Better still, it's votes
they're counting on
For themselves.
They lose 10%,
you gain 10%.
If you make a difference,
If i win by less than
100,000 votes,
You got your million.
Otherwise...
I don't need them,
i won't vote them.
I'm not selling you
an option.
I'm selling you the right
to vote the shares.
If they make
a difference,
You got a million.
If they don't,
half a million.
I've prepared the papers.
Left the numbers blank.
You can have your lawyers
look at them.
Everybody looks out
for their own self-Interest,
Don't they?
"What's in it for me?"
Isn't that what it's
finally all about?
Yes. Very good.
Very good.
When do we run
in the times?
Tomorrow, sir.
Times, barrons,
forbes...
Boston herald.
Next week, major cities
in new england.
Take this copy
and slide it all over
To the right.
And up in the corner here,
put that picture of me.
You look good
in that shot.
Oh, god.
Look at him.
He's trying to look
like desmond tutu.
All right, richard,
get our ad agency.
Call barbaro.
Call pinelli.
Barbaro, pinelli.
Yeah, and where's that
phone call from tokyo?
I'm on it.
Taxi! Taxi!
Thanks, ron.
[Telephone rings]
Mr. Garfield's office.
I expect him back
at 5:30.
Thanks, connie.
I'll ask him
to phone you.
Bye-Bye.
Look, i found it.
Mrs. Sullivan.
She insisted
On waiting for you.
I would appreciate
a few moments of your time.
Certainly. Hey,
come on in the office.
Hold my calls.
Will do.
Come on in.
Have a seat.
Did your daughter
send you?
'Cause she's full
of clever moves, you know.
No, she didn't.
She'd be very upset
with me if she knew.
I like kate. She's
quite the tomato.
She must have taken
after you, huh?
You're very kind.
I would hope this meeting
will be held in confidence.
Everybody's looking for
confidence these days.
You want
a cup of coffee?
Cup of tea?
Glass of water?
You needn't be sociable,
mr. Garfield.
Harriet, i'll have
a cup of coffee.
Yes, sir.
You mind if i smoke?
I'd like to tell you
why i'm here.
Good. Shoot.
I'm here to plead
for our company.
I want to talk to you
about hopes and dreams...
Traditions.
Would you care
for a doughnut,
Mrs. Sullivan?
We've worked so hard
to build this company.
We're debt-Free,
And we don't deserve
to lose it.
I want you to call off
your fight with us.
There's a trust fund
in my name
With $1 million in it.
I'll turn it over to you
if you'll go away.
You don't want to
do that.
We'll buy back
your shares at cost,
Plus you'll have
$1 million profit.
Interesting.
I know $1 million
isn't much money to you,
But if i had more,
i'd give it to you.
Who are you
doing it for?
Money's not
that important to me.
Well, it is to me.
Then accept my offer.
You'll have more money
Than most people make
in a lifetime.
$1 million.
It's not enough.
Go home, mrs. Sullivan.
I'd hoped to appeal
to your sense of decency.
I'm sorry.
I don't take money
from widows or orphans.
I make them money.
Before or after
you put them out of business?
Whew! What a woman.
Harriet, why do i
always bring out
The best in people?
[Ringing]
Kate: hello?
Hello?
Oh, please.
[Click]
Arthur!
Get the car.
Arthur.
I'm sorry, sir.
There's no answer
in miss sullivan's apartment.
Well, try it again.
Maybe you dialed it wrong.
[Elevator bell]
No!
It was--
Um--Um,
excuse me, bart.
What are you doing here?
Who's bart?
I'm on my way out.
You should have called.
I need to talk
to you.
I don't have time to talk.
I'm late.
I have something
very important to tell you,
And i need to talk
to you now.
You look beautiful.
Who's this guy?
Excuse me, lawrence.
Call me tomorrow.
I can't talk tomorrow.
It won't keep.
I want you
to marry me.
Let me put it
another way.
I want to marry you.
You thinking it
over?
What are you
talking about?
What do you mean?
I want you to be
my wife.
We belong together.
Bart:
katherine.
I'm going to the opera.
I got to go.
No, no, kate...
You're
the last thought i have
When i fall asleep
at night
And the first
when i wake up
In the morning.
I want to be with you
forever and ever.
I want to have babies
with you.
Babies?
Yeah.
You see,
i got to do this now
Because after i win,
i wonder maybe
You won't ever want
to speak to me again.
You can't win because
i'm gonna win.
I know how important
it is to you,
But you're not
going to win.
This is what's
killing me.
I want you.
I need you. I love you.
I just don't
want to lose you.
Bart: katherine.
Keep your pants on,
will you, bart?
I've got to go.
The opera.
La traviata.
You don't want to miss
the first act.
It sets up
the whole thing.
It's a wonderful
production.
Have a good time.
I'm going to lose her,
arthur.
* good king wenceslaus
looked out *
* on the feast of stephen *
* when the snow lay
'round about *
* deep and crisp
and even *
* brightly shone the moon
that night
* though the frost
was cruel... **
Oh, i've been looking
for you.
Any time you're ready.
You ok?
Yeah.
Just going over
in my mind
What i want to say.
They're putting
speakers outside.
I think
every shareholder
Within driving distance
is coming.
I feel as if
we're harry and bess
On election night.
Harry truman
was a better man than me.
He slept
on election night.
I haven't slept in days.
Talk to me.
Tell me.
I'm scared.
I'm scared that...
Time has passed us by.
I'm scared i don't know
this new environment.
I'm scared
that what i do know
Doesn't count
for anything anymore.
Things have changed.
Whatever happened
To people serving
each other?
I don't want
this man to win.
I'm not scared.
I'm just proud.
I'm proud of the
business we've built.
I'm so proud of you.
And if what we are
Counts for nothing
anymore,
Then that's their
failing, not ours.
It'll be all right.
Just go out
and tell the truth.
Go out and give 'em
hell, harry.
[Water spills]
[Laughing]
Good luck to us all
today, bill.
I feel we're going
to be just fine.
Looks like they've come
from everywhere--
New york, boston.
There's ozzie.
Happening all over,
isn't it?
Everybody looking out
for themselves.
So, did you get your
golden parachute, bill?
Did he finally promise
to take care of you?
Lord of the manor,
house on the hill.
Said he didn't want
to talk about a funeral
While there was
no corpse.
Well, time to go.
Bill.
How are you
going to vote?
Oh, boy. They're out
in droves, arthur.
They got the kids here.
Why do they always
bring the kids, arthur?
That's right--
Hooray, hooray.
Down with garfield.
[Horns honk]
Ok, tv crews.
Financial news network,
here we come.
[Shouting]
Mr. Garfield!
What are your plans
For new england
wire and cable?
Make the stockholders
richer.
Will you liquidate
new england wire and cable?
And if so,
what about the workers?
My obligation
is to the stockholders.
The board of directors
make that decision.
Will they lose
their jobs?
Come on,
answer the question.
Come on, mr. Garfield!
How do you
feel about
The outcome of
today's proxy vote?
I feel confident
That the shareholders
will vote their consciences.
I have every confidence
in this company's future.
Could i have
your attention, please?
Welcome to...
New england wire and cable's
annual stockholders' meeting.
I'm william j. Coles,
your president...
And i'm sure...
[Applause]
I'm sure
that everyone here realizes
The most important item
on the agenda is...
The election
of the board of directors.
Now, there are
staff members
Passing out the ballots.
Right now,
i am very proud
To introduce to you
a man
Who could accurately
be characterized
As a legend in the wire
and cable industry.
The chairman of the board
Of new england
wire and cable,
Mr. Andrew jorgenson.
[Applause]
Give 'em hell, andy!
It's good to see
so many...
Familiar faces,
so many old friends.
Some of you
i haven't seen in years.
[Laughter]
Thank you for coming.
Bill coles,
our able president,
In the annual report
has told you of our year,
Of what we accomplished,
Of the need
for further improvements,
Our business goals
for next year
And the years beyond.
I'd like to talk to you
about something else.
I want to share with you
some of my thoughts
Concerning the vote
that you're going to make
In the company
that you own.
This proud company,
Which has survived
the death of its founder,
Numerous recessions,
One major depression,
And two world wars,
Is in imminent danger
of self-Destructing...
On this day,
in the town of its birth.
There is the instrument
of our destruction.
I want you to look at him
in all of his glory--
Larry the liquidator.
The entrepreneur of
post-Industrial america
Playing god
with other people's money.
The robber barons of old
At least left something
tangible in their wake--
A coal mine,
a railroad, banks.
This man leaves nothing.
He creates nothing.
He builds nothing.
He runs nothing.
And in his wake
lies nothing
But a blizzard
of paper
To cover the pain.
Oh, if he said,
"I know how to run your
business better than you,"
That would be something
worth talking about.
But he's not saying that.
He's saying,
"i'm going to kill you
"Because at this particular
moment in time,
You're worth more
dead than alive."
Well...
Maybe that's true,
But it is also true
That one day
this industry will turn,
One day when
the yen is weaker,
The dollar is stronger,
Or when we finally begin
to rebuild our roads,
Our bridges,
The infrastructure
of our country,
Demand will skyrocket.
And when
those things happen,
We will still be here,
Stronger because of
our ordeal,
Stronger because
we have survived.
And the price
of our stock
Will make his offer
pale by comparison.
God save us
If we vote to take his
paltry few dollars and run.
God save this country
If that is truly
the wave of the future.
We will then
have become a nation
That makes nothing
but hamburgers,
Creates nothing
but lawyers,
And sells nothing
but tax shelters.
And if we are
at that point
In this country
Where we kill something
Because at the moment
It's worth more
dead than alive,
Well,
Take a look around.
Look at your neighbor.
You won't kill him,
will you?
No.
It's called murder,
And it's illegal.
Well, this, too,
is murder,
On a mass scale.
Only on wall street,
They call it
maximizing shareholder value.
And they call it legal.
And they substitute
dollar bills
Where a conscience
should be.
Damn it!
A business
is worth more
Than the price
of its stock.
It's the place
where we earn our living,
Where we meet
our friends,
Dream our dreams.
It is, in every sense,
The very fabric that binds
our society together.
So let us now,
at this meeting,
Say to every garfield
in the land,
Here we build things,
We don't destroy them.
Here we care about more
Than the price
of our stock.
Here...we care
about people.
[Cheering]
Thank you.
And now i'd like
to introduce
Mr. Lawrence garfield.
[Booing and hissing]
Excuse me--Please.
Let's show a little courtesy,
ladies and gentlemen.
Mr. Garfield
is the president
And the chairman
of the board of...
Garfield investments.
Mr. Garfield.
[Booing]
No!
Get out of here!
Amen.
And amen.
You have to forgive me.
I'm not familiar
with the local custom.
Where i come from,
You always say amen
after you hear a prayer.
Because that's
what you just heard.
A prayer.
Where i come from...
That particular prayer
is called
The prayer for the dead.
You just heard
the prayer for the dead,
My fellow stockholders,
And you didn't say amen.
This company is dead.
I didn't kill it.
Don't blame me.
It was dead
when i got here.
It's too late
for prayers.
For even if
the prayers were answered
And a miracle occurred
And the yen did this
And the dollar did that
And the infrastructure
did the other thing,
We'd still be dead.
You know why?
Fiber optics.
New technologies.
Obsolescence.
We're dead, all right.
We're just not broke.
And do you know
The surest way
to go broke?
Keep getting
an increasing share
Of a shrinking market.
Down the tubes.
Slow but sure.
You know,
At one time,
there must have been
Dozens of companies
making buggy whips.
And i'll bet
the last company around
Was the one that made
The best goddamn buggy whip
you ever saw.
Now, how would you
have liked
To have been a stockholder
in that company?
You invested
in a business,
And this business
is dead.
Let's have
the intelligence,
Let's have the decency
To sign
the death certificate,
Collect the insurance,
And invest in something
with a future.
"Ahh, but we can't,"
Goes the prayer.
We can't because
we have a responsibility,
A responsibility
to our employees,
To our community.
What will happen
to them?
I got two words for that.
Who cares?
Care about them?
Why?
They didn't care
about you.
They sucked you dry.
You have no
responsibility to them.
For the last 10 years,
This company
bled your money.
Did this community
ever say,
"We know
times are tough--
We'll lower taxes,
reduce water and sewer"?
Check it out.
You're paying twice
what you did 10 years ago.
And our devoted employees
Who've taken no increases
for the past three years
Are still making twice
what they made 10 years ago.
And our stock--
1/6 what it was
10 years ago.
Who cares?
I'll tell you.
Me.
I'm not your best friend.
I'm your only friend.
I don't make anything?
I'm making you money.
And lest we forget,
That's the only reason
any of you
Became stockholders
in the first place.
You want to make money.
You don't care
if they manufacture
Wire and cable,
fried chicken,
Or grow tangerines!
You want to make money!
I'm the only friend
you've got.
I'm making you money.
Take the money.
Invest it somewhere else.
Maybe...
Maybe you'll get lucky,
And it'll be used
productively.
And if it is,
You'll create new jobs
And provide a service
for the economy
And, god forbid,
Even make a few bucks
for yourselves.
[Laughter]
And if anybody asks,
Tell 'em you gave
at the plant.
[Laughter]
And by the way,
It pleases me
that i am called
Larry the liquidator.
You know why,
fellow stockholders?
Because at my funeral,
You'll leave with
a smile on your face
And a few bucks
in your pocket.
Now, that's a funeral
worth having.
The ballots
will be marked
And deposited
in the ballot boxes
At the rear
of the hall.
Thank you.
Yeah.
Ladies and gentlemen,
please.
May i have
your attention, please?
I will now read
The results
of the balloting.
To retain
the present board--
1,741,416.
For the opposition--
2,219,901.
Not voting--
176,111.
Mr. Garfield,
your slate is elected.
Congratulations,
mr. Garfield.
lawrence.
You ok, boss?
You want some chicken
soup or something?
Mmm.
Pie?
No.
How about some
of that carrot cake
You like so much?
No.
Well, carmen,
we did it again.
I can always
count on you, can't i?
Another barrelful of money.
Not bad for a kid
from the bronx.
I love money.
[Intercom beeps]
Mr. Garfield,
Kate sullivan
is on the line.
Are you in or out,
mr. Garfield?
Hello?
You're a greedy,
arrogant,
Self-Absorbed,
Overbearing--
Avaricious?
I have a proposition
for you.
Are you ready,
lawrence?
Ready.
Air bags.
Air bags?
Every car in america
is about to have one.
Did you know
that air bags
Are made from
stainless steel wire cloth?
Did you dump bart?
The mitsushimi company
of japan
Is ready to make
a long-Term deal
With new england
wire and cable
For the production
of...
[Breathy voice]
air bags.
I love the sound
of your voice.
[Breathy] well, here comes
the best part, lawrence.
You sell wire and cable
back to the employees.
They modernize
and re-Equip the plant
And turn out
air bags.
What's in it for me?
They'll pay
28 bucks a share.
You like?
They'll go to 30.
30? You think so?
Why not? We'll talk
about it at dinner--
I'll see you in an hour.
Lunch. Tomorrow. 1:00.
You know where.
Strictly business.
Oh, yeah, yeah.
Wow!
Did you hear that,
carmen?
Harriet! Call my manicurist,
call the barber,
Call the florist,
Call arthur, tell him i want
two tickets to the opera
Tomorrow night.
Puccini.
We're back in business!
Whoo-Hoo!
It's money that i love.
Captioning made possible by
warner bros.
Captioned by the national
captioning institute
--Www.Ncicap.Org--