HI removed, cleaned and corrected by Tronar
My name is Diana Henriques.
As an investigating reporter
for the "New York Times,"
I had been covering the Bernie Madoff scandal...
...from the day it began.
After months of requests
and correspondence,
I was finally able to sit down
and interview Bernie Madoff...
...on August 24th, 2010.
Until today,
...his only visitor,
apart from lawyers...
...has been his wife.
He has not answered
any independent questions...
...about his crime...
...except when standing
in a courtroom...
...responding to a judge.
On those occasions,
...he seemed stiff,
almost rehearsed.
But in our conversation,
...he seemed relaxed,
...unfailingly candid,
...earnest, and trustworthy.
That is his talent
and his curse.
That is what enabled him...
...to pull off the biggest Ponzi scheme on record.
$65 billion.
Bernard L. Madoff...
...inmate number 61727054.
In overseas trading today,
...the Nikkei was down over 8%...
...with Australia's benchmark not far behind.
The crisis shows no sign of ending...
...as DOW futures are down
this morning on Wall Street...
...and Main Street continues to find itself...
- ...in the crosshairs of the largest meltdown...
- Shit.
Since the Great Depression.
Investors and banks are holding onto their cash...
...until more certainty can be
flushed into financial markets.
Let's go now to Bob Summers...
...with a story on yet another city...
...going under
from the mortgage crisis.
I'm in Fresno, California,
where if you look around...
Just let me lead it off.
It's completely fucking crazy.
We can't back down on this one, Andy.
We're not gonna back down.
We're gonna hold firm.
What, no good mornings,
no hellos?
Dad?
What's going on?
You're giving out
175 mil in bonuses?
- I am.
- In December?
We've had a very strong year.
The year's not over.
We don't know where we're gonna land.
I wanna reward people.
I want them to feel good about
the work they've done here.
There's a reason that the
bonuses go out in February,
...especially in this climate.
You're not hearing me.
It's important that people can
take care of their families.
Isn't it better to play it safe?
Hang on to any windfall just in case?
I'm paying out the bonuses now.
But that's crazy. It doesn't make any sense.
- Peter.
- Bernie, come on.
This isn't a fucking debate.
I'm paying out the bonuses now.
I'm taking care of everybody.
Dad, are you all right?
What's going on with you?
I'm okay.
Okay, are you sure?
Bernie, just tell them.
Tell us what?
What is it, Dad?
What's going on?
I have to talk to you.
You can. You know you can.
I know.
Fucking fish bowl here.
Fucking fish bowl.
Huh?
Everybody can see everything in here.
How come we never got fucking blinds?
- Hello?
- Hello, Ruth.
- Hi.
- The boys and I are heading home.
Why?
I have to talk to you all.
Oh, okay.
- Yeah, we'll be home soon.
- All right.
Is it your health?
No.
Let's go in the study downstairs.
There's no way to... to say it.
None of it is real.
It's all one big fucking lie.
- What is?
- The advisory.
It's a fraud.
There are no investments.
What are you talking about?
Of course there are investments.
- I made them up.
- They're on every statement.
- I ma... I made them up.
- I've seen the trades.
They're fake.
It's all fake.
Basically, just a big Ponzi scheme.
What's a Ponzi scheme?
I took money from some people.
I gave it to others and I never...
...there's nothing left.
There's supposed to be 50 billion.
There's absolutely nothing.
It's all gone.
I spoke to Peter...
...I told him I'm gonna
turn myself in next week.
How could you do this?
- I just couldn't stop...
- Bullshit.
It got bigger and bigger
and it just wouldn't stop.
Bullshit.
- I didn't mean for it to get like this.
- No, no, no, no.
You can't do this.
I'm your son.
Dad. Dad, how could you do this?
I'm gonna set you guys up.
Yeah. It's... it's all gonna be okay.
There's still
a few hundred million left.
I'm gonna...
I'm gonna make sure...
...that you guys are all taken care of,
...the rest of the family,
some loyal employees.
It's all gonna be good.
I just need a week.
Set us up with what?
With stolen money?
He's a criminal.
He's gonna spend his life in jail.
- Dad, how could you do this?
- You're not my father.
I explained to them that
it wasn't malicious,
...that when I started this problem...
...or this crime...
...that is was something that I thought
I would be able to work my way out of.
But that became impossible.
The harder I tried, the deeper
I dug myself into a hole.
But it comes down to one thing.
I refused to accept the fact,
...could not accept the fact...
...that for once in my life I had failed.
I couldn't...
I couldn't admit that failure.
And what was that failure?
Shortly thereafter, I...
...I think I went back to the office.
Andy was there.
I saw Andy.
Did you two speak?
He did mention that...
...that he, uh...
...he and Mark were consulting with a lawyer.
Well, as it turned out,
he went to see Martin London...
...much honored lawyer, retired.
- He's Mark's father-in-law.
- Yes.
He'd invested a substantial
amount of money with you, right?
Well, more than some, less than others.
Jesus fucking Christ.
50 million?
50 billion,
with a "B."
Jesus fucking Christ.
All right, I'm in Hartford.
I'll be there at 3:00 PM.
You have to understand
the money management business...
...was operating from a small office.
- Yeah, the office is on a separate floor.
- The 17th floor.
- It's always seemed successful.
- A ton of clients, I think.
- Hedge funds.
- I know he'd even turn people away sometimes.
- But all the trades...
- Yeah, the trades go through European counterparties.
That's why he has the London office.
And then upstairs on the
19th floor is market making.
- Which is where we work.
- These are not my immediate concerns.
But if he plans to spend the week...
...distributing his ill-gotten gains...
...amongst his relatives,
...employees, his friends,
...then this is not over.
This is a crime in progress.
So what are you saying?
We have to turn him in?
You don't turn him in.
You're an accomplice.
Yeah?
Okay, it's all fine.
Yep.
Who is it?
The FBI is here.
I know why you're here.
Well, we're here to find out...
...if there's an innocent explanation.
There is no innocent explanation.
Is there someplace we can talk, privately?
In there.
He said he'd been operating a Ponzi scheme
...since the 1970s.
He was so matter-of-fact about it.
He wasn't nervous,
he wasn't afraid.
He was just very casual.
Well, sir, he claims to have acted alone.
Yes, sir.
I'll bring him in.
Hi, it's Ruth.
Are the boys there?
They're not there.
He won't be coming in today.
Sir, you're gonna have to remove your belt,
...your shoelaces, your tie,
...and any jewelry.
- This?
- Yep.
Credit card, cash,
...anything in your pockets, sir.
Turn around, please, sir.
Hands behind your back.
Palms together.
Put that stuff away.
And call Ike Sorkin.
What happened on the night of December 9, 2008?
My brother told me...
...that his investment advisory business...
...was a Ponzi scheme.
And what was your reaction
to hearing that Mr. Madoff...
...was operating a Ponzi scheme?
Well, I was in total shock.
In your first interview with the government,
...you stated that you idolized your brother.
- Is that correct?
- Yes, and that's correct.
Why did you idolize your brother?
Well, because he was brilliant.
Everywhere you go,
people talked about Bernie.
He was a true pioneer.
Everyone in the industry,
...including the highest-ranking
officials at the SEC,
...believed that my brother was
...one of the most honorable
and successful traders...
...of our time.
Nobody believed that more than I did.
I revered him.
I trusted him... implicitly.
- Sorkin.
- Ike, it's Bernie.
Uh, I'm down at FBI headquarters...
...handcuffed to a wall.
Bernie, don't say another word.
We arrested him this morning.
Was he okay?
I put the cuffs on him myself.
He went quietly as though he expected us.
To be honest,
...he looked relieved.
You did the right thing, son.
Turn to the right.
Yeah, the FBI just processed him...
...and they transferred him over to Pearl Street.
Yeah, we're heading in right now.
So you were making money off of the trades.
There were no trades.
- What do you mean there were no trades?
- I made them up.
- Weren't there statements?
- Every month, they were fake.
Purchase dates, they were fake;
Shares, they were fake;
Options, they were fake;
Returns, they were fake.
So when was the last trade you executed?
15 years ago.
Who else knew?
I acted alone.
When did he tell you he started this Ponzi scheme?
He didn't.
And the entire time he was
running it, you had no idea?
- No, I didn't.
- And what was your role at the firm?
I ran the firm's NASDAQ desk in the late '90s,
...added the rest of the
market-making desk in 2001,
...and moved to the proprietary
trading desk in 2003...
You're not answering my question.
What exactly is your role at the firm?
I'm only in the office a few days a week.
I've been building a separate
business called Madoff Energy...
Sir, what is your exact title at BLM?
Director of Proprietary Trading...
...and Codirector of Trading.
And where did the money for these loans come from?
The loans that allowed you
to buy your loft in SOHO,
...your house in Greenwich,
your house in Nantucket.
I assume from the money he
made through investments.
On the private advisory side?
- Yes.
- On the 17th floor?
- And you never asked what went on the 17th floor?
Of course I did.
- You did?
- Yes.
- But...
- But what?
He would always say,
"You run your business
and I'll run my business."
And you never thought...
...to follow up on those questions?
- You don't understand...
- You're right, I don't.
I don't understand...
...how you could work in the
same office as your father...
...for 20 years and suspect nothing.
Nothing?
Who are some of your father's clients?
I'm not privy to all of them,
...but, um,
Jeffry Picower was a big one.
Fred Wilpon and Saul Katz of the Mets.
HSBC, Royal Bank of Scotland,
...some family friends, Marty.
But he wouldn't talk about
who or what he did for them.
Our money was with him as well.
So you were never suspicious of your father?
Never?
Do you not understand who he was?
I think we're all beginning to understand...
...exactly who your father is, Mr. Madoff.
He wasn't just my father.
You know, he was fucking idolized.
We're talking about a man...
...who created the modern market as we know it.
He created NASDAQ.
He's Chairman of NASDAQ.
He's Chairman of the National
Securities Clearing Corporation,
Chairman of the International
Chairman of the National
Association of Securities Dealers,
...which was FINRA before FINRA fucking existed.
Chairman of the SIA Trading Committee.
- Okay, we understand your point, sir...
- No, I don't think you do.
Chairman of the National
Business Conduct Committee.
- Sir, we understand.
- Member of the SIA Federal Regulation Committee.
- Sir, that's enough.
- Chairman of the NASD Small Order Execution Committee.
I mean, you're asking me...
how I didn't know.
Well, I'm asking you.
You're the FBI,
you're the SEC.
You investigated him before,
...so I'm... I'm asking you...
...how the fuck did you not know?!
Sir, we are not the focus here.
You are.
You're saying that you never stepped foot...
...on the 17th floor?
No.
And why not?
♪ Sleigh bells ring ♪
♪ Are you listening ♪
♪ In the lane ♪
♪ Snow is glistening ♪
What happened on the morning
of December 11th, 2008?
Uh, I was in my office...
...and, uh, I got a telephone call.
Who was on the phone?
It was, uh, Bernie Madoff.
What did Bernie Madoff say to you?
Yeah?
Frank, my brother, is in the office...
- What?
- with the FBI.
What the fuck?
How old were you when you first started working...
...for Bernie Madoff?
I was 19 years old.
In what capacity had you known him?
Oh, well, he was my boss.
What type of work had you done
for him over the years?
Uh, really anything he asked me to.
Everything from, you know, running errands...
...to running his investment advisory department.
Did you know why the FBI was
at Peter Madoff's office?
Yes, I did.
And what did that mean to you?
Uh, it meant that I was going to jail.
Why did you think you were going to jail?
Because I was well aware of
the nature of the operation.
And what was the nature of the operation?
It was a fraud...
...simply put.
I always thought that Bernie...
...would be able to make it good, you know?
He had money here, he had money there,
he moved stuff around.
There was always a lot of moving parts.
Maybe I was lying to myself.
I don't know,
but I... I thought he...
I thought he could cover it.
What the hell is this?
Bernie's been arrested for securities fraud.
The SEC's getting a court order...
...to seize control and shut us down.
Without an investigation?
What could they possibly know?
Whatever Bernie told them.
Sir, who was that gentleman?
He's... uh, he works here.
- Where?
- Uh, on the 17th floor.
There's a 17th floor?
Annette, Bernie's been
arrested for securities fraud.
The SEC and the FBI are upstairs right now.
What?
The hell does that mean?
We need your keycard, ma'am.
Come on, come on, come on.
Please, please.
Open it.
FBI! Everyone stop what what you're doing!
FBI! I said stop what you're doing right now.
Move away from the computer!
Sir, FBI. Do not touch that computer.
I said move away from the computer!
Hey, Dan, walk this group out.
The advisory was a completely separate business,
...a completely separate entity.
Never the two should meet, ever,
...and they didn't.
And I made it that way on purpose, obviously.
What about your brother? Peter's in trouble.
- Yes.
- Because he trusted you. He did what you told him to.
- He did.
- And you told him to do things that exposed him...
...to this criminal liability
he's facing right now.
How did you...
justify that, Bernie?
sleep with that?
I guess the way I could sleep with it...
...is that I knew that
Peter didn't know anything...
...even though I had him do things...
...which he didn't realize
...could've implicated him in this...
...in this, um...
...crime.
Bernie was always needling people.
He would find your weak spot
and he would poke at it.
I mean, that was Bernie and
he could be a real bastard.
But not like this.
I mean, not stealing
people's money.
I mean, at first,
I started thinking,
"My God, you know, did one of the
grandchildren get kidnapped?"
"Was the 10 million
ransom money?"
What 10 million?
The 10 million that Ruth came in...
...and withdrew
from her Cohmad account
...and transferred into her Wachovia account.
I mean, I...
what do I know?
I mean, I'm always watching
crime stories, you know?
I fall asleep every night to "SVU."
And you're saying on December 10th,
Ruth Madoff withdrew $10 million
from her Cohmad account...
...and transferred it to a personal account?
Yes, but that is not unusual.
I mean, think of it like having an ATM
...in your, you know... your living room.
Except, you know,
when things are going on,
...you wonder.
Mommy's here!
Don't forget your ball.
We're gonna go to Connecticut for a few days.
You know it might snow?
No mention of his arrest yet.
- It's my mom.
- Don't answer.
You know what Flumenbaum said...
...no contact.
Don't screw around, Mark.
- Hi, Mom.
- Hi, Mark.
Honey, I'm, um... I'm with your father...
...and in order to release him on bond...
...they need four signatures.
It's a $10 million bond.
- What?
- Ugh, I know. Can you believe?
Anyway, can you get down here?
Uh, I'll text you the address.
Mom,
...do you understand what he's done?
No, honey, Mark,
I know you're angry,
...but he's your father.
I'm not doing it.
End of discussion.
Mark.
I'll try Andy.
What do you mean by misunderstanding?
We couldn't get your sons to sign.
They wouldn't sign?
I'm sorry, Mr. Madoff.
The boys wouldn't sign the bond?
I'm very sorry, sir.
Who... did you talk to them or did...
No. Your wife was on the phone with each of them.
Their mother did and they didn't...
they wouldn't...
Um...
Well, there's no money involved in it.
So did they understand that?
Yes.
Hmm, I don't know.
Marc, it's Daniel Horwitz.
We couldn't get the four signatures,
...but I can get you Ruth...
...and, um, Peter Madoff's.
Okay, hold on.
Will you submit to, um,
home detention...
...with electronic monitoring and surveillance,
...homes in Manhattan, Montauk, and
Palm Beach will be pledged,
...and yours and Ruth's
passports will be surrendered.
Are those terms okay with you?
Um, yeah.
He says yes... Great.
- Okay.
- "The Journal" just went online with the story.
We have 20 minutes before the
press descends on this place.
Let's do this.
Mr. Madoff.
It's very strange and troubling news...
...out of Wall Street tonight.
Former NASDAQ Stock Exchange
chairman Bernard Madoff...
...out on $10 million bond.
This man with a stellar reputation...
...seems to have taken a whole lot...
...of very smart people to the cleaners.
The man they trusted the most with their money,
...a NASDAQ chairman 18 years ago,
...is now confessing to authorities...
...he cheated them of billions of dollars.
And there's a bunch of big-time investors...
...wondering, how a guy named Madoff...
...made off with their money.
What's gonna happen, Bernie?
- I don't know.
- Are you gonna go to jail?
Probably.
For how long?
- I don't know, Ruth.
- For a long time or a little?
I don't know.
- What?
- I don't know.
Are they gonna take the apartment away?
- What about the houses?
What about the boys and the grandkids?
- Ruth. Ruth, enough.
- Look I just wanna know if...
I'm sorry if I have questions, Bernie.
I'm sorry if I'm a little scared, okay?
It's just you always keep me in the dark.
I keep you in the dark to protect you.
Yeah, well, it doesn't feel that way anymore.
I just wanna know what's going on.
Please, Bernie, don't keep me in the dark anymore.
Just tell me.
Tell me.
Tell you what, Ruth?
Just tell me,
I don't know...
...what you did.
I met Ruth when she was 13. I was 16.
A friend was having a party in his basement.
Something had happened to the jukebox.
It got knocked around
when he was moving it,
...so the only song it'd play
was "Sh-Boom" over and over.
She was this tiny, little blonde...
...with enormous blue eyes.
Just gorgeous.
Very funny, too.
You remember that actress Goldie Hawn?
- I do very well.
- Yeah, that was Ruth.
She'd wake up every morning
without a care in the world.
Very lively, very bubbly.
Popular, too.
- Were you popular?
- Oh, yeah.
I mean, I was a lifeguard at the time.
Best job I ever had.
I mean, why just be some
regular schnook on the beach...
...when you can be in a guard tower,
...everyone looking up at you?
- And you get paid.
- Did Ruth ever get jealous?
For the rest of the summer,
...she laid out right next to the...
the guard tower every day.
Sometimes I'd whistle down at her
...and she'd look up and call me a dog.
But I liked having her there.
It felt good.
I mean, we've basically been together
...every day since the night we met.
It's our 51st anniversary coming up.
Mm.
How do you think you were
able to keep it all separate?
For 16 years,
I kept this secret from my wife,
...my brother,
...my sons.
How I was able
to do that...
...and maintain any degree of sanity,
...well, it's, uh...
...that worries me when I think about it.
♪ Oh, oh, yes ♪
♪ I'm the great ♪
♪ pretender ♪
♪ Ooh, ooh ♪
♪ Pretending ♪
♪ that I'm doing well ♪
♪ Ooh, ooh ♪
♪ My need is such ♪
♪ I pretend too much... ♪
- Those are fresh?
- Yes, sir.
They are really fresh?
- Fresh this morning.
- Not freshly frozen?
- No, sir.
- Fresh, fresh, okay.
♪ I'm the great ♪
♪ pretender... ♪
Check all the plates.
Make sure that none of them are dirty, please.
I don't want anybody coming
here and eating on a dirty plate.
They pick up a napkin,
...you pick up a napkin...
...and then you have dirt under here like this.
This one. See?
Dirty plate.
Make sure they're all clean.
What was your job title...
...at Bernard L. Madoff Investment Securities?
Chief compliance officer.
I never had any financial interest in the firm.
Bernie made it clear that there
was no prospect for partnership.
♪ Boom, ba-doh ♪
♪ ba-doo, ba-doodle-ay ♪
♪ Oh, life could be ♪
♪ a dream ♪
♪ If I could take you ♪
♪ up in paradise up above ♪
♪ If you would tell me... ♪
Eleanor.
So who's the more handsome brother,
him or me?
All right, we've all heard this one, Casanova.
- Come on.
- In my opinion?
Be honest.
- Peter's way more attractive.
- Oh.
So you've got a thing for barrel-chested
bald men with big stomachs?
Screw you!
In fact, Bernie,
...when I first met Peter,
I said to myself,
"My God, this man looks
just like Lee Majors."
- Handsome.
- Thank you, Eleanor.
Yeah, that was 25 years ago.
Back then, even you were attractive, Eleanor.
Stuff it, Bernie.
You know you got a thing for me. Do not lie.
You're right, I do.
- Come here.
- You know I love you.
I gotta make the rounds.
Peter, do not let him get to you, that one.
I'm used to it, believe me.
♪ Sh-boom, sh-boom ♪
♪ Ya, da, da, da ♪
♪ da, da, da, da, da, da ♪
♪ Sh-boom, sh-boom ♪
♪ Ya, da, da, da ♪
♪ da, da, da, da, da, da ♪
♪ Sh-boom ♪
♪ Sh-boom, sh-boom... ♪
The fuck you looking at?
Annette, you have a fucking heart attack,
I'm not giving you mouth-to-mouth.
♪ Ya, da, da, da ♪
♪ da, da, da, da, da, da... ♪
Just so we're clear.
♪ Ya, da, da, da, da, da ♪
♪ da, da, da, da, sh-boom. ♪
Behind you is not the place to be.
Your accounts at Madoff Securities...
...had a total of approximately $50 million.
- Is that correct?
- Yeah, that's correct.
Did it strike you as absurd...
...that someone with just
a high school education...
...should have that kind of money?
No! I was very, very lucky.
Kind of like winning the lottery?
Kind of like winning the lottery.
Did it occur to you...
...because you had this great account...
...and it was worth so much,
...there must be something fraudulent there?
No. I never thought of the word fraudulent.
In my experience,
...and I mean this, there's only
four different types of pussy.
Okay?
I'm dead serious.
You got your... let me show you.
I just saw one.
All right, right there.
See there?
That's your Honda Civic pussy.
Gets you where you wanna go.
No shame in this pussy at all.
Reliable.
You just, you know,
...you're not gonna be proud to be seen...
...riding around town in it, am I right?
- Nothing against her.
- What's going on?
It's the world according to Frankie over here.
Right there. You see that there?
That's your Buick Regal pussy.
Okay, a step up from the Honda.
Uh, generally they're cleaner, okay?
Roomier, you fit more passengers in there.
I guess there's pros and cons to that in a pussy.
You know, lovely pussy.
Nobody's gonna mistake it for
a Benz, though. Am I right?
Am I right, Robert?
Okay, thank you. God bless you.
I just want you to know,
...despite everything you see,
Andrew is not from money.
- Oh, no, no.
- He's not from money.
I... I'm not... I'm not...
I know you might think he's a rich guy,
...but he's not.
We're from nothing.
My father was broke.
We're not rich people.
We're humble people.
- Okay.
- You understand?
Yes.
- Come here.
- Yeah. Oh.
Oh!
I'm gonna have to get out the hose...
...and spray him.
Next up,
my personal favorite.
I just saw one.
There. Now, don't make it obvious.
Right there.
That is your Lincoln Continental pussy.
Beautiful. Just... it's just right.
You know what I mean?
Like Goldilocks just right.
It's not too fancy,
it's not too plain.
It just...
it's just comfortable.
It just... it just fits.
No, no, it's like an old pair of slippers...
...except instead of your foot,
you put your cock in it.
- Am I wrong?
- You have a daughter, right?
Yeah, Sophie.
She's wonderful.
I can't wait for you to meet her.
And who's the father again?
Um, uh, John,
...my... my ex-partner at Urban Angler.
And you two never married?
Um, no. No.
If I had had a baby out of wedlock,
...my father would have taken
me out back and shot me.
I'm not kidding, he would've shot me.
No, no, stay with me...
...and hold all questions till the end.
- Okay.
- Right there, you see that? Ugh.
There it... read it and weep.
It's your Mercedes-Benz pussy.
Right? Look at it.
I mean, it's beautiful.
It's just a feat of vaginal engineering.
No, it handles just great.
It's sleek, it's tight,
...it looks good, it feels
good, it smells good.
But...
a lot of upkeep. Yeah?
Payments are murder and you
gotta wax it, you gotta polish it,
...you gotta... talk to it,
ou gotta listen to it, eh?
And, most importantly,
...you gotta remain ever vigilant...
...that nobody fucking jacks it, right?
You don't have to worry about that
'cause you'll never get
near anything like that.
So don't worry about it.
Is it fair to say...
...that as a result of all of these lies,
...you got rich?
Well, I didn't get paid per lie, ma'am.
As a product of the fraud
that was Madoff Securities,
...you got rich, correct?
Yeah, that's correct, yeah.
You built, as you described,
...a lavish home in Bridgewater,
New Jersey, correct?
- Well, define "lavish."
- Sure.
- Uh, how many bedrooms did it have?
- Five.
- How many bathrooms?
- Seven.
- How many acres?
- Did it have a swimming pool?
- Yes, it did.
- Did it have a tennis court?
- It did not.
- Did it have a pond?
- Yes, it did.
So would you consider...
...seven acres, seven bathrooms,
...five bedrooms, a swimming pool,
...a pond, a lavish home?
I guess I might.
♪ Reaching out ♪
♪ Touching me ♪
♪ Touching you ♪
♪ Sweet Caroline ♪
♪ Bah, bah, bah ♪
♪ Good times ♪
♪ never seemed so good ♪
♪ So good, so good ♪
♪ so good ♪
♪ I've been inclined ♪
♪ Bah, bah, bah ♪
♪ To believe ♪
♪ they never would ♪
♪ Oh, no, no... ♪
Whoo!
Come here.
♪ Sweet Caroline ♪
♪ Bah, bah, bah ♪
♪ Good times ♪
♪ never seemed so good ♪
♪ So good, so good ♪
♪ so good ♪
♪ I've been inclined ♪
♪ Sweet Caroline ♪
♪ Bah, bah, bah... ♪
Hey, by the way, you know
Stephanie and I went last weekend...
...to see that house in Nantucket?
- You know...
- You should try the lobster.
- Oh, no, no, it's okay.
- Oh, trust me on the lobster.
Try the lobster.
Hey!
- Dad, you know I got...
- Can you get my son...
- ...a lobster, please?
- ...a weak stomach.
Would you get him a lobster? Just...
Would you like me to get you the lobster?
What are you asking him for?
Just get him a lobster.
- He'll thank us both later, okay?
- Seriously...
So, what's the price tag on this house?
Uh, they got it at, like, six and a half,
- ...but we'll talk them down.
- That's what they're asking for?
Yeah.
I mean, it's, like, special.
It's, like... it's got a pool
looks out over the ocean.
- It's unbelievable.
- Uh-huh.
But I figure we can
get them down a bit.
Now, wait.
That's the way you bring the lobster?
Apologies, sir.
Why don't you bring it back,
...take off the claws, open it up.
I mean, I pay enough for this whole thing.
Don't you guys know how to serve a lobster?
- Apologies. I'll be right back.
- Okay, just bring it back properly.
- I mean, what is this?
- You wanna come see it with me?
- We could go down next week and...
- I'll go see it.
We can work on the price, too.
Yeah, six and a half,
maybe we can start at five.
- That would be nice.
- We could probably take a boat from Montauk.
- We can go out of the harbor...
- Good idea.
Okay, thanks.
So... don't eat that, eat this.
- Don't eat...
- I don't like lobster, Dad.
I don't even know why we had that.
I guess your mother...
'Cause it's not good on my stomach.
Hey, uh,
...take this away, will you, please?
Yes, sir.
- There you go.
- Apologies, sir.
Okay.
One thing he's good at is apologizing.
♪ You, you ♪
♪ You ♪
♪ Ah... ♪
I guess I'm just wondering...
...what if something happens to you?
We don't know the first thing about the advisory.
- Frank will handle it.
- Come on, Dad.
With all due respect, Frank's...
Frank's what?
Frank's an idiot.
You know, Frank
never went to college.
I heard Frank,
comparing women's vaginas to automobiles...
...earlier today.
Whether Frank is refined enough
for your taste is irrelevant.
He's good at his job.
If something were to happen to me,
...he'd fill you guys in on all
the details you need to know.
And what if Frank decides to screw you?
I mean, I don't even know how much
you're worth. Is it a billion?
Two billion?
Three?
What if there's three and he says there's two...
...and takes a billion and
rides off into the sunset?
Calm down, calm down. Everything is
written down in a safe deposit box.
If something were to happen to me,
...you consult with our lawyers,
and they'll handle it.
They'll fill you in on everything.
Everything, huh?
- That's right, everything.
- Everything? You know, good luck.
This conversation is impossible.
- I don't understand why you can't understand...
- Impossible!
What I just said to you.
You know, why is it that whenever
this conversation comes up,
...you find a way to wriggle out of
giving me an answer?
It comes up because you bring it up.
No, because I'm... we're trying to plan.
Well, if you don't bring it up,
it won't come up.
You know, I'm just trying to get a...
a basic sense...
You don't have to get a sense of anything, Mark.
- You don't have to get a sense of anything.
- Why is that too much to ask?
- I've told you this is something I don't talk about.
- Dad. Dad!
Listen to me.
- I don't understand!
- Listen, what is wrong? Are you a fucking idiot?
Are you a fucking idiot?!
I mean, answer me!
- I don't understand!
- No, you don't understand!
You don't have to fucking understand!
You're asking me about taking over the advisory...
...and yet you can't even follow
a simple fucking instruction...
...to shut the fuck up!
You don't understand.
Leave it alone.
Okay.
I'm sorry.
- Good night.
- I love you, Dad.
Love you. Good night.
♪ Hey, nonny, ding, dong ♪
♪ a-lang, a-lang, a-lang ♪
♪ Boom, ba-doh ♪
♪ ba-doo, ba-doodle-ay ♪
♪ Oh, life could be ♪
♪ a dream ♪
♪ If I could take you ♪
♪ up in paradise up above ♪
♪ If you would tell me I'm ♪
♪ the only one that you love ♪
♪ Life could be a dream ♪
♪ sweetheart ♪
♪ Hello, hello, again, sh-boom ♪
♪ and hopin' we'll meet again ♪
♪ Oh, life could be a dream ♪
♪ Sh-boom ♪
♪ If only all my precious plans ♪
♪ would come true... ♪
People here always ask me how come I never ran.
But the truth is it didn't even occur to me.
I guess it's because I never thought...
...of what I was doing was stealing.
Well, it was a $65 billion Ponzi scheme.
People lost their life savings,
they lost their homes.
Their lives were destroyed.
You didn't think of that as stealing?
People felt safe with you.
- Yeah, but these were...
- And yet...
...you were betraying them all.
Well, but these people, you know,
...they had a little greed in them, too.
There was a little bit of, you know...
...look, you know, and they
didn't wanna look too hard.
They looked just far enough.
- So they're accomplices in some way, too.
- Bernie.
Accomplices because they trusted you?
Accomplices because you
were so trustworthy,
...you seemed so trustworthy.
Yeah, but there's a lack
of honesty on their behalf,
...an unwillingness to take responsibility
for their behavior.
- Your investors?
- Yes.
It takes a lot of chutzpah...
...for you of all people to say that.
You know...
...now that I think of it,
...my greatest failure...
...or maybe it's my greatest weakness...
...is I've always wanted to please people.
And that's...
...that's one that can get you into trouble.
I've been here all fucking morning!
- I wanna go upstairs.
- Sir, nobody's going upstairs right now.
I wanna see somebody in charge.
- Right now, I'm in charge.
- Who are you protecting?!
And you need to back up right now.
- We're talking about my fucking life savings!
- I told you right now!
- Do you understand?
- You need to back up right now, sir.
- Hello, Madoff.
- I'm in the fucking lobby.
I wanna come up.
Sir, I am not able...
...to give you permission
to come up here right now.
Where is my fucking money?!
You have to call the advisory arm.
- I can give you their number.
- Fuck you, you fucking thief!
Oh, my God.
Unusual circumstances did not exist for Bernie.
Take 9-11.
When those towers got hit,
...everybody in the whole entire office...
...was gathered around the TV.
Who was crying?
Who was hysterical?
Not Bernie.
He kept his head down
and he continued to work.
And it is not like...
...he did not know anybody...
...in those buildings.
As with every event...
...of personal devastation,
...they remember
exactly where they were...
...and what they were doing...
...when they learned
they were ruined.
The grayish white paper...
...rolled out of Mary Thomajan's fax machine.
The fax was from the small feeder fund...
...she had trusted for 18 years...
...telling her that all her money...
...had been invested with Madoff,
...who had been arrested.
She later recalled,
"In the 50 seconds it took
to read that fax,"
"I went from being
a multi-millionaire..."
"...to having my life savings wiped out..."
"...and life as I knew it
altered forever."
Robert Halio's son called him
at his retirement home...
...in Boca Raton with the news.
It's all gone, Dad.
I don't...
I don't know what to do.
95% of his wealth...
...had been entrusted to Madoff
and was now gone.
Mr. De la Villehuchet...
...had written his brother a letter that said,
"If you ruin your friends,
your clients,"
"...you have to face the consequences."
He then positioned a trash basket...
...to protect the carpet...
...and slit his wrist with a box cutter.
Tim Murray,
a property manager in Minnesota,
...was traveling
and nearly drove off the road...
Fort Lauderdale...
- Richard Freedman...
- David Iselin...
Time to pay the piper, Bernie.
Presumably...
...presumably with the life
savings of another piper.
Just...
This was the worst pyramid scheme...
...since the actual pyramids.
- Ruth loves to go to the California Pizza Kitchen.
- Yeah.
And they say that her favorite dish there...
...is the veal Scallo-Ponzi.
Listen, I have something to tell
you that's really important.
I have your money!
I can get it to you.
Okay, I guess you're not there.
They can see right in.
- They can see right in.
- What?
We... we don't have any curtains.
They can see right in.
Hold on, let me call you back.
- Catherine, it's gonna be fine.
- No, they're gonna be looking in...
...with their long lenses
and we'll be trapped.
They're gonna get bored
just standing around.
I'm not the story.
We've gotta get curtains
right now.
Shit.
Hi, how are you?
I'm all right.
You?
I've been better.
I'll bet.
- Mommy, Mommy.
- What?
- Is that Ruth Madoff?
- Jessica, not another word.
It's okay.
No, none of it is.
There she is.
- Hi, Sarah.
- Oh, hi.
Is Gisele here?
I was wondering...
...if she might be able to fit me in today.
I haven't had my hair colored
in God knows how long.
- Um, I think she's...
- You know, don't worry.
- I'll find her.
- Uh...
I've been coming here for 15 years, Pierre.
I understand.
We have too many clients...
...who have lost their money
because of your husband.
But I don't trust anyone else.
I'm very sorry,
...but I can't afford to
risk my reputation.
What about a house call?
I can pay extra.
- I'm sorry...
- Pierre.
...but I have to ask you to leave now.
I'm sorry, Ruth.
- Shit.
- Ruth!
- What are you doing?
- Nothing!
What are you doing?
- Looking for something?
- My lighter.
Well, aren't there matches in the drawer?
- No.
- No? What do you mean?
- There's always matches in the drawer.
- Well, we're out.
Where'd you last see it?
If I knew where I last saw it,
I wouldn't be looking for it, Bernie.
I'm such an idiot.
How did I get to be this age...
...without doing anything on my own?
What are you talking about?
I... I didn't do anything, Bernie.
I never did one thing on my own.
I... I don't have a career,
I don't have a name,
I don't... I don't have
any friends of my own.
The only thing I have are regrets.
That's all I got to show for myself.
- Regret after regret.
- Ruth, do we have to go into this now?
I got a lot on my mind.
I'm going away and who knows
if I'm going to come back.
- Why would you say that?
- I'm not saying for certain...
- No, Ike said that you'd be able to...
- Forget I mentioned it.
You can't do that.
I'm not ready.
I... I'm, I'm not ready to be alone.
You're all I have.
The boys don't speak to me.
No one speaks to me.
I'll...
I'll go crazy, Bernie.
I'll... I'll go crazy all alone.
I'll go crazy, Bernie, I will.
Hi.
Leave a message after the tone.
Bernie!
Bernie, you there?
Bernie?
Come on, pick up.
I know you're hiding that 50 billion somewhere,
...you piece-of-shit cocksucker.
I hope you enjoy getting your
ass raped every night,
'cause you're going away for a long time.
Hasta la vista, you kike motherfucker.
What are you doing?
I can't live like this.
Slogging through,
...being miserable to no good end.
What's the point?
You know, I was thinking earlier...
...this... this isn't even about me.
This country needs a villain,
...someone to send to the gallows...
...so everyone can feel okay
about living under a rigged system.
I don't give a rat's ass, Bernie.
Well, it'll be better once I go.
What's with the jewelry?
It's the only thing the court didn't freeze.
I'm gonna wrap it all up,
...give it to family,
...and then kill myself.
Why would you kill yourself?
Because I'm tired of being hated.
I don't even understand it.
I...
you got yourself into trouble.
You couldn't get out.
What do I have to do with it?
Why does the world hate me?
They all think I'm some kind of a mastermind.
Take it as a compliment, Ruth.
They say all these
horrible things about me.
They say
I... I was your bookkeeper.
- They say...
- You weren't my bookkeeper.
I did maintain the records the first year.
That was in 1960.
It was just you and me.
I mean, but you weren't even a real bookkeeper.
No, but I'm just saying don't make
it seem like I didn't pitch in...
...because I even came back, remember?
- Yeah, but then we hired a real bookkeeper.
- And I helped with payroll.
- We hired a real bookkeeper.
- Right, so why are they making it seem...
...like I...
like, I'm involved with all this stuff?
Because they're out for blood, honey.
That's why.
They just wanna...
But anybody in the know knows
you weren't the mastermind.
- That's nonsense.
- Oh, well, thanks.
I already wanna kill myself.
Are you trying to make me feel worse?
No, but I...
You, uh...
...you'd commit suicide?
With what?
I don't know. I haven't figured that part out yet.
Something nice.
Maybe Ambien.
How much Ambien do we have?
Enough to open a fucking pharmacy.
What about these?
Klonopin?
Same thing.
Just put it in here.
Do have yourself a merry little Christmas.
It's a great song and you'll be
hearing Judy Garland sing it...
Can't we just have quiet?
I can't fall asleep unless I watch something.
You just took a whole
fucking bottle
...of Ambien, Bernie.
Sleep's not gonna be your problem.
My mind races.
Fine.
Our last night on Earth
...will be you, me,
and Judy Garland.
- How romantic.
- Let's not get started, Ruth.
We had a good life, didn't we?
Yeah,
...until you ruined it.
♪ Have yourself ♪
♪ A merry ♪
♪ little Christmas ♪
♪ Let your heart ♪
♪ be light ♪
♪ Next year ♪
♪ all our troubles ♪
♪ Will be out of sight... ♪
♪ Have yourself... ♪
Pop-pop!
♪ Make the yuletide gay ♪
♪ Next year ♪
♪ all our troubles ♪
♪ Will be miles away... ♪
♪ Once again... ♪
Hello?
♪ As in olden days... ♪
Poppop!
Hello?
♪ Happy golden days ♪
♪ Of yore ♪
♪ Faithful friends... ♪
Mark, Andy.
Uh,
I'm glad you came.
I have so much I wanna tell you.
So much
I wanna tell you.
I never...
I never wanted any...
I never wanted
either of you
...to... to...
...to, you know...
I just never wanted
either of you to...
...it just...
...sometimes things in life happen...
...that you don't even...
You know, there's a lot that
I never really wanted to...
...to tell you.
Uh,
I'm glad...
I'm glad you're here.
♪ Once again ♪
♪ As in olden days ♪
♪ Happy golden... ♪
Good evening.
It is a day that will be in bold print...
...in history books.
Black Monday,
October 19th, 1987,
...when the stock market
went into a free fall,
...losing more in one day...
...than it did on Black Tuesday in 1929.
Fucking rigged.
How to fuck the little guy.
I wonder if I can count on you.
Of course.
Pop-pop!
- Can I count on you?
- Pop-pop!
We took a big hit today.
Lost over a billion and change.
You know how with a split-strike
conversion strategy...
...the stock options offset losses?
It's like insurance.
A fucking meltdown like this,
would have been a nice strategy.
If only we had it in place...
- ...before the fucking...
- No ifs.
No ifs.
And we tell no one.
We tell no one.
Pop-pop!
Basically, we're picking winners
of yesterday's horse races?
Yeah, so if anyone double-checks
our trades, we got it all there.
- All winners.
- Fine.
Make sure the books show...
...that the London office
is clearing the trades...
...so no one upstairs in
market-making is involved.
Not my brother,
not the boys, no one.
- Understand?
- Yeah, of course, of course, yeah.
No one.
Erwin's last words to me,
...the last thing he said was,
"Bernie will take care of everything."
He's gone, and...
I don't know what to do.
It's gonna be okay.
You can take all of Erwin's other accounts...
...his savings, life insurance, everything...
...and you can put it all in his account here.
God bless you, Bernie.
Pop-pop!
- Pop-pop!
- Daniel!
- Pop-pop?
- Yeah?
Are you gonna die in jail?
♪ Somehow... ♪
Ruth. Ruth.
Ruth, I need more pills.
Ruth.
Have you no shame?
Hello?
No remorse?
Have you no conscience?
You steal from widows,
...you steal from charities,
...you steal from Elie Wiesel,
a Holocaust survivor.
You prey on your own people.
You steal from your own people.
Have you no shame!?
- Huh?
- Well, we're still here.
Mr. Markopolos, it's all yours.
Thank you, Mr. Chairman.
My team and I tried our best
to get the SEC to investigate...
...and shut down the Madoff Ponzi scheme...
...with repeated and credible warnings to the SEC
...that started in May 2000.
- We knew that...
- Ruth.
What?
You wanna watch this Harry guy's testimony?
Who?
Harry... I don't know, I can't pronounce it.
What's he testifying about?
Me.
Over a nine-year time span.
If a $50-billion Ponzi scheme...
...doesn't make the SEC's priority list,
...then I wanna know who sets their priorities.
What made you think that
Bernie Madoff was a fraud?
The key tip-off...
and it took me about five minutes...
...to figure out that he was a fraud...
...I'm gonna give you a hand
signal and I'm gonna show you...
...what his performance return line looked like.
It went in only one direction...
up.
It never had variation like the market does...
...like... like this,
but then I did...
- Who is this guy?
- He tried to warn the SEC about me.
- And what happened?
- They ignored his warnings.
- So what's the point?
- What do mean what's the point?
Well, what's the point of all this?
Well, he's saying that basically,
...he handed the SEC the evidence...
...and they didn't follow up on it.
Oh, so a government agency is incompetent.
- Mm-hmm.
- Yeah, and that's news?
No, look, I've been saying that for years.
And I have firsthand knowledge.
This fucking cocksucker walks
in and out of the building...
...with this jacket on.
What the fuck is wrong with him?
Bern, the guy's asking for our DTC account number.
What are we gonna do?
I mean, all my years dealing with the SEC,
I've never seen this
enforcement.
Who the fuck does this guy think he is?
Boss, if we don't give the guy the number,
...it's gonna be obvious that
we're hiding something.
Yeah, but the way he just fucking
walks in here like that,
...no fucking suit or nothing.
- No, I know.
- What kind of fucking arrogance?
The jacket's annoying,
but, Bern, please focus.
If we do give it to him,
...uh, one call to the DTC and that's it.
Game over.
We're just here for a routine exam.
We haven't done one in 10 years.
- You were just here.
- Uh, we... we weren't.
- DC Inspections was.
- We don't talk to DC.
So, uh, tell me
about this article.
Yeah, I was very bothered by this.
I mean, why would they make me look fat?
Excuse me?
I mean, look at my face.
Look at my cheeks.
I look like a fucking porpoise.
Well, um, yes, but I'm
referring to the allegations.
What about it?
Lori Richards has all this information.
I sent it to her in a file.
They have it.
As I told you, we're a very large organization.
- We don't talk to each other.
- You don't talk to DC?
N-no.
It... it's, uh...
This is the problem with the SEC.
I've been saying this for years.
I mean, you have to have
better communication.
How are you supposed to be able to do your job...
...with a fraction of the information?
Well, we're trying to get all of the information.
Well, don't you think you
should start by talking to DC?
I mean, I got... my whole office here
...is wondering what's happening.
You come in with that jacket,
...it embarrasses the hell out of all of us.
And this?
It's a fucking cartoon.
It's an old article.
It's four years old.
And you're asking me questions
about an old article...
...with a silly cartoon?
And you haven't spoken to DC.
Are we, um... are we waiting on your lawyers?
I never have lawyers in the office...
...when I'm talking to regulators for two reasons.
One, I'm not doing anything wrong.
Two, I know the rules better than most...
...because I drafted a majority of them.
And we haven't met before,
...but we have very strong relationships.
And I was on the short list for SEC director.
Yes, we...
we know that.
If you need anything at all,
I'll be in my office.
There's no such thing as an inconvenience.
- Thanks.
- I'm here.
Oh, um,
...by the way, are these securities with the DTC?
- Of course.
- We're gonna need your account number...
...just so we can verify the assets.
Oh, Bern, you're fucking killing me.
646.
646. Great, thank you.
Do you mind if you take that jacket off...
...before you go out there?
- Oh, um...
- Just...
Sure.
One call.
All the SEC had to do
was make one call...
...and they would've seen
that everything was fake,
...that there was nothing there.
But they never called.
You just gambled that they wouldn't call?
It was more than a gamble. It was...
...it was a leap of faith,
if you will.
You wait, knowing what they will find...
...if they make that call.
I can't imagine what that was like.
It was... it was
excruciatingly difficult.
At some point, you figured...
I figured that they didn't do it.
They just didn't follow up on it.
If you didn't plan on killing yourself...
...or going into hiding,
...how did you think it would end?
Well, it was almost like, uh...
...it sounds horrible to say it now...
...but I just wanted the whole
world to come to an end.
When 9-11 happened,
I thought this was the only way out.
The world would come to
an end, I'd be dead,
...and everybody would be gone.
But, I mean, I could've kept it going.
I could've covered everything.
Even after the fall of '08,
I had enough commitments of
cash that would've come in.
So I could've,
you know... I... I...
I just got tired.
I knew by Thanksgiving I was gonna give it up.
I was gonna stop.
Financial turmoil in the US.
Wall Street in crisis mode.
Wall Street on red alert.
Bear Stearns has effectively gone under.
The largest bankruptcy in US history.
- Unprecedented.
- This is really shaking the foundation of Wall Street.
A lot of money
and a lot of jobs.
America's economy is facing
unprecedented challenges.
All of this taking a devastating toll on stocks.
Single biggest point drop ever.
I'm sorry to bother you.
I just got another call you're gonna fucking love.
- Yeah, go ahead.
- Bank Medici's
...pulling out 450 million, Bern.
Stanley Chais has been
draining us all goddamn year,
...and this is on top of Fairfield's withdrawals.
I delivered for these fucking
people for fucking decades...
...and now they're all running
for the fucking hills.
Bern, we can't keep getting
hit with these redemptions.
We gotta find a way to conserve.
I think we should lower the returns.
Are you kidding?
That'll cause a bigger panic.
They'll all pull out, the greedy fucks.
We can't do that.
Well, we gotta do something.
We're treading water like
a fucking paraplegic here.
- I was just saying...
- Hold on, let me get rid of this idiot.
The joke on the street is that
Bernie's like the Jewish T-bill.
- Very funny. I'm on the phone. I'm on the phone.
- He's that safe.
I'm on the phone.
I'll introduce you guys later.
He's gonna love you.
See if you can rattle Fairfield's cage.
In the meantime,
I've got a few ideas.
- Fairfield?
- Yeah.
All right.
- Uh-huh. Nice, nice.
- Not in a bathing suit.
Me neither.
- Hey.
- Hey, kid.
I heard you're the one who hustled...
...those penny stocks in that
shitty office you had downtown.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Yeah, that's me.
Can you believe I've known this man for 50 years?
Carl, listen, I wanna tell you something.
Not now.
There are some real opportunities
in the market right now...
...and I wanna make you
aware of them.
- Not now, Bernie.
- I know, I know.
- Not now.
- I know. I wouldn't tell you about them...
...unless they were really,
really important, okay?
I don't want you mad at me you missed out.
All right.
How much do you want me to put in?
250.
- On top of the 300 million I already have with you?
- Yes.
The market in shambles?
It's plummeting, but now is
the time to take advantage.
- I'm so exposed...
- That's exactly why I'm proposing this to you.
I'm afraid I'll be arrested
for public indecency.
Oh, I'm not doing it with everybody.
- It's just a few people.
- All right, all right. Enough.
- Okay, and you are family.
- I'll tell you.
Listen, I'll think about it.
- Okay.
- Okay?
But don't take too long.
In all seriousness,
don't take too long.
Please don't take too long.
- Carl...
- I said it. I will think about it.
- Period.
- I live you, I respect that.
Thank you very much.
Fucking rich people.
Parasites.
You're in a mood.
I gotta take this.
Well, I just got off the phone...
...with that cocksucker at Kingate.
He's pulling out 260 million.
Do these fucking people not understand...
...how a fucking split-strike works?
- Do they not understand?
- Hold on, I got Fairfield calling me back.
Hold on.
Yeah?
Hey, Rick Jarvis.
We met at the club a few
months back with Solomon.
Well, look, while I got your attention,
I just exited this private equity
venture with a five X return.
I'm looking to put that money to
work right away this quarter.
Well, unfortunately,
that's not possible.
I haven't told you how much.
- Well, it really doesn't matter.
- $100 million.
I'm sorry, but the fund...
...is fully subscribed for the quarter.
- Even in this market?
- My clients know not to worry.
I know how to avoid the pitfalls.
Okay, I want in
this quarter, all right?
Whatever restrictions you wanna put on it,
...you know, I'll park this money
with you for a long time.
It's not about the money.
It's about pushing clients aside.
I can't do that.
I have to sacrifice someone,
...a loyal client to me,
in order to accommodate you.
Unless it's really, really worth it...
I am talking about giving you
$100 million.
That's, uh, not gonna do it.
So what's it gonna take?
I have to do what's ethical.
- I can't let you jump the line.
- I'll go 150 if you let me.
- Love to help you, but I can't.
- 175.
Fully subscribed.
- 200.
- I wish I could.
I'm just thinking if I... no.
225?
250.
275.
$300 million.
How far do we gotta go?
Just tell me.
If you go above four,
we might have something.
400.
I can do that.
We got a deal.
I gotta take this phone call.
Yeah?
I don't know who the fuck
I was just talking with,
...but if this guy checks out,
we just picked up a good piece of change.
Well, the shit is definitely
hitting the fucking fan.
I got Fairfield-Greenwich on the line.
- You want me to patch you in?
- Go ahead.
Hey, Bernie. We catching you at a bad time?
You tell me. I got a back spasm
that's fucking killing me.
- Bernie. Bernie.
- What's going on?
- Can I just get one minute?
- Not...
Just one minute to introduce you.
- I can't talk.
- Just one minute!
- Yeah?
- Look, Bern,
...you're basically the only fund
that hasn't gotten hammered.
You're the one place clients
can turn to for liquidity...
...without taking huge losses.
It's the winner's curse.
What... what, am I supposed to be flattered...
...that you just cashed out
a billion and a half dollars?
You gotta put a stop
to these redemptions...
...because if you don't,
just know there's plenty of money out there...
...that would love to take your place.
- Is that a threat?
- You can take it any way you like.
Look at you all dressed
up and no place to die.
- Hello, Jeffry.
- Come on, Bernie, there's no need for stress.
I haven't made many withdrawals.
Although, that's probably
something we should discuss, hmm?
I did wanna tell you that there
are some real opportunities...
...in the market right now
if you're interested, Jeffry.
- Hmm.
- What do you think?
- We should be talking...
- Mrs. Madoff!
- Mr. Picower.
- Your husband doesn't look well.
You should attend to him, hmm?
You okay?
What's wrong with him, Picower?
He's one strange, sicko fuck.
Oh, by the way, my sister,
...she's worried about the economy...
...and she was thinking about investing...
...the rest of her savings with you.
- Would that be okay?
- Yeah, sure.
Walter, I'm not a fucking money
market fund, do you understand?
If you don't stop these withdrawals...
...and replace the money
before the end of the month,
...then I'm gonna cut you off!
I'm gonna close the whole
fucking Fairfield account!
Yes!
Do you hear me?!
Oh, shit.
What the...?
- I hated that. No, I didn't!
- You loved it.
- You came out of there, you said... don't lie.
- Oh, I did not!
- You're such a liar.
- You're a liar.
Sweetheart, is that a little bit too rare?
This is good.
- Everything all right?
- Yeah.
Did you wheel your
luggage into the bedroom?
- Why?
- Did you wheel your luggage into the bedroom?
Well, I certainly didn't bring
it in through the window.
But you smudged the wall by the door.
You scuffed it with your roller bag.
Well, string me up and feed me to the dogs.
I'm sorry I scuffed a wall, Bernie.
Emily, was just asking about Wall Street, Dad.
Yeah,
...how is Wall Street, Papa?
She's working on her MBA.
Dad, future head of Madoff Securities.
That's right. Watch out, guys.
I asked how's Wall Street, Papa?
Wall Street is good.
Dad says things are bad at Wall Street.
Well, Dad told you that,
but things are fine.
Why are they bad?
What did I just say?
I asked a question. Why is it bad?
I told you they're not bad.
Why don't you just eat?
Well, if it's not bad, why
do they call it a meltdown?
- Why don't you tell me?
- How am I supposed to know?
- That's why I'm asking you.
- Do you read "Barron's," huh?
Do you read the "Wall Street Journal"?
- Why don't you tell me?
- I just asked a question.
You are my granddaughter
and you're an eight-year-old...
...and you shouldn't be asking
me questions like that.
- I don't feel like talking about Wall Street.
- Hey, Dad.
- I don't feel like... be talking about Wall Street.
- Dad.
- I'm here having dinner with my family.
- That's enough.
Bernie, what's wrong with you? She's just curious.
Because she doesn't know what
the hell she's talking about.
She's eight years old.
I gotta get grilled by this kid.
- Why are you being so mean?
- I got so many other goddamn things
I'm worried about on Wall Street...
...and this kid's asking me
about how Wall Street is!
- Shut up and eat your food!
- Dad!
It's okay, sweetheart.
Bernie, stop it!
What's wrong with you?
Now you're playing the good guy.
- Honey, it's okay, it's okay.
- Taking her side.
- She's just curious.
- Now I can't eat.
- It's okay, it's okay.
- She's an eight-year-old kid.
What's the matter with you?
You're just too smart.
It's okay.
I wanna know why you're acting this way.
The fucking market
is a bloodbath.
- Ah! God damn it.
- Hey, hey, hey, hey.
Take it ea... Dad.
Fucking thing.
What's going on?
Are you all right?
I started these
blood pressure pills.
Makes me dizzy.
- Maybe you should take a couple days off.
- No, I can't.
I have to be at the office
first thing in the morning.
- Founder of Home Depot.
- Reschedule.
- You know...
- This fucking thing.
If you ever trusted me...
...to help you with the advisory,
...you know, I could handle
this kind of thing for you.
It's my business, not yours.
Well, what happens when you're gone?
- I'm not having this discussion with you.
- It's a legitimate question.
- What is it, Dad?
Tell me.
What is it?
Is it that I'm not cut out?
- Are you not listening?
- Just be honest with me.
- Just tell me.
- Do you not see what I have to deal with,
...the shit that I have to
go through on a daily basis?
No, that's why...
that's my point.
The fucking shit that they put me through?
That they're trying to fuck me all the time?
Steal from me?
Do you think you can do that?
Do you think you can deal with that?
- Yes, I can.
- I don't think you can deal with it.
Bullshit.
I don't think so.
You can't stomach that stuff.
That's not in you.
Andy, maybe, but not you.
What?
Wait, what are you saying?
Are you saying that Andy...
...what are you saying?
Andy's better
at his job than I am?
- Mark.
- I go to that fucking office every single day.
I do the same thing that he does.
I gave you a fucking business to run.
Are you not happy with that?
Was that not good enough for you?
It is definitely good enough for me, Dad.
- I'm just trying...
- Well, then shut the fuck up...
...and give me a little fucking gratitude.
Say, "I'm... thanks, Dad."
Can't you do that?
What, do you think the whole
fucking world owes you something?
The whole fucking world owes you nothing.
You gotta work for it,
and I always say this with your mother.
This is the problem with
having money, an education.
Nothing is earned.
You want something,
you gotta fucking work for it.
What, you don't think I have?
For you, it was installing sprinklers.
For me, it was digging ditches
on a construction crew.
I never would have started Home Depot
if I hadn't had that experience.
Ken, I wanna be respectful of your time,
...so I'm gonna get right to it.
I'm starting a new highly exclusive fund.
It's gonna have just five investors.
Same split-strike conversion strategy...
...that's performed so consistently.
But, frankly,
...this fund's gonna have even higher returns.
The only thing is that it relies...
...on the market volatility
that we're seeing now,
...so I gotta put the money together right away.
Your current fund's been running
for a while, hasn't it?
It has.
Decades.
Double digit returns every year.
And you're promising even better returns
for the new fund?
It's a unique opportunity, Ken.
Uh-huh.
So I'm asking myself only one question.
What if I'm a
longtime client of yours...
...and, uh,
how would I feel...
...getting shafted for new customers?
There are other people
that I do other funds with,
...but I don't wanna include them
in this because they're not...
- Whoa, whoa, wait a second.
- they're not the ones...
Okay, just a second.
I'm a little confused.
You got this fund,
you got that fund,
...you got people who are long-term
customers and you're not gonna...
Those people are already taken care of.
We have... we have other funds with them.
Bernie, I don't... I don't know
what you're trying to say.
- Well...
- I'm confused.
The new fund is getting money
before the other people?
- That's not what I'm saying.
- That's exactly what you're saying.
I'm not saying that.
They are taken care of.
I have other arrangements with them.
Something is not kosher here.
- Something.
- No, it's all kosher.
I think it's not kosher.
I think it's total bullshit.
That's what I think.
It's hitting me the wrong way.
Something is wrong here.
I think you're full of shit,
that's what I think.
I'm getting the hell out of here.
Is that guy in?
You're kidding me.
All right, well, uh,
between Medici, Kingate,
...and the fucking Spaniards,
...that's minus 1.5 billion right there.
Thanks to Fairfield,
we're down 980 in November...
...and we're looking at at least
minus 580 in December, Bern.
We write that fucking check,
it's gonna bounce.
We got 300 million left.
What do you wanna do?
Hey, Carl, this is great news.
I just want you to know
it's great news.
- All right, take care.
- Okay, of course, of course.
- Great. Okay, talk soon.
- That's it.
- Thank you.
- Okay.
He's in for 250.
All right.
That's not nothin'.
No, but it's not enough.
No, it's definitely not enough.
What about that schmuck from Palm Beach?
Oh, no, no, no, it was, like,
20 fucking questions with that guy.
He wanted to know why our controller...
...was based in Bermuda.
Why our auditor was a
one-man operation
...working out of a strip mall
in upstate New York.
It was a whole fucking thing with that guy.
It's not an easy conversation.
I've already laid the groundwork for this.
You're hardly in the office anymore.
I think what I say is that...
Andrew, sweetheart,
...you don't have to sell him on a decision
...that you're making for yourself.
- This is about you.
- I know, I know.
It's just hard because I know
he's gonna be disappointed.
Well, I'm not.
I am very proud of you.
Thanks.
Okay, I'll see you when I get home.
I love you.
Dad?
You okay?
What's wrong?
Oh, fucking back spasms.
It's all seized up.
This is the only position that doesn't kill.
I'm sorry.
Can I get you something?
I already took a bunch of pills.
- What's up?
- Uh, nothing.
- We can talk later.
- Look, what do you need?
No, forget it.
Well, fucking spit it out.
Well, I wanna talk to you about a few things.
Then spit it out.
Come on.
Well...
well, look... um
I'm thinking about taking
office space somewhere else.
You're thinking about leaving the business?
I'm ready to strike out on my own.
And here I was worried about
the business I handed you.
Look, I have professional goals of my own.
And I'd like to run my own company someday...
...and it's obviously not
happening here anytime soon.
You're pretty fucking selfish, Andrew.
You got some fucking nerve.
I've worked here forever
and I'm still not a partner.
It's your name on the doors,
as you love to say.
You obviously can't see how
selfish you're being right now.
Let me ask you something,
do you know what kind of offers
I've gotten to sell this firm?
- Do you?
- No, I don't.
The last one was from Goldman
for a billion dollars.
What?
Why didn't you take it?
Because I didn't wanna take it.
I need it like I need a fucking hole in the head.
And the main reason I didn't take it
...is because of you boys,
that's why.
Because one day,
I want this to be yours
...with your name on the door.
I mean, why else would you think I'd do it?
You're welcome.
- You're welcome.
- Yeah, I heard you.
Bernie, how far... does your wife know?
Bernie, does your wife know?
People familiar with the case...
...tell CBS News
federal investigators...
...are ripping apart
20 years of fraud...
...inside Madoff's firm,
...moving beyond Bernie,
...looking at sons Andrew and Mark...
...who directed trading activities,
...and brother Peter, the company's...
...chief compliance officer.
None have been charged
with any wrongdoing.
So, now as Bernie Madoff prepares
- for what may be his last night of comfort in...
- Hey.
What is it?
I don't know,
maybe it's a waste of time,
...but I thought that I would try to write.
Write what?
I don't know, a book.
Ah, it sounds stupid.
No, it doesn't sound stupid.
It may not be any good,
but I... I, um...
...this is just the opening.
Do you wanna hear it?
Yeah, I'd love to hear it.
"Up until December 10th, 2008,"
"I spent the entirety of my life..."
"...in awe of my father."
"I judged every accomplishment,"
"...every failure, professionally
or personally,"
"...against the life he lived."
"His approval meant everything,"
"...maybe too much,"
"...and for as long
as I can remember,"
"I worked as hard as I could
to make him proud."
"And then one day,"
"I found out that my father
was not the man I thought."
"He was a criminal,
a man I didn't respect."
"And yet this man, my father,"
"...is the same man
who taught me right from wrong,"
"...taught me to be fair
and decent and honest,"
"...taught me about the
importance of character,"
"...what it means to be a husband,"
"...and, most importantly,
how to be a father."
"I am the son of Bernie Madoff."
"I used to think that I
could never escape that."
"Now I'm certain I won't."
"Why is it so hard to believe..."
"...that those closest to him
wouldn't see him as a criminal?"
"Why is it so hard
to believe that his son..."
"...would think his father
could do no wrong?"
"When I look
at my youngest son, Nick,"
"I fear the day
when he's old enough to ask..."
"...what his grandfather was like."
"What kind of man was he?"
"If I tell him he was evil,"
"...how can I explain that I'm"...
"...that I"...
It's good, Mark.
It's really good.
Yeah, I... I don't know.
So, is it a plea deal?
No. He's just pleading guilty.
So, he's just gonna plead guilty...
...to all the charges and that's it?
It looks that way.
- So there will be no trial?
- No.
Have you read what they're saying about us?
Every fucking day
they're calling for our head...
...every paper, every blog.
How are those people gonna know we're innocent
...if there's no trial?
How?!
- How?
- The sooner he is locked up...
- Bullshit.
- This will be over.
It's gonna fucking linger.
The questions, the suspicions,
...the fucking paparazzi camped out...
Are they not charging him with conspiracy?
No, he won't plead guilty to conspiracy.
Mr. Madoff, are you going to plead guilty?
They should charge him anyway and force a trial.
If they took Dad to trial, what would happen?
Just think about it, Mark.
You're talking about putting the richest...
...and most powerful people
in the world up on that stand.
You're talking about JP Morgan,
Chase, HSBC, Swiss Banks.
You're talking about
the world's financial system on trial.
Now, I'm not a conspiracy theorist,
...but trust me,
that will never happen.
Ever.
So, no,
...there won't be a trial.
The public won't know the truth.
And we'll be left to fend for ourselves.
I don't understand, Mark.
Do you want a trial?
No.
Well, what do you want?
I want my life back.
We're not here. Leave a message.
Mom again.
Hi, it's me again.
Your mother.
I don't know why I'm calling.
I feel like such a moron...
...leaving all these messages,
...begging you.
I don't know.
I miss you.
I miss Stephanie, I miss Audrey.
I haven't even seen little Nick.
I haven't even seen my grandson.
What am I supposed to do, Mark?
I'm stuck.
I'm so sorry.
I'm sorry for what he did.
I don't know what he was thinking.
I can't even fathom it.
I just don't understand
why you're so angry at me.
I know you want me to leave him,
...but I can't just abandon him.
How am I supposed to
just walk out...
...of a 50-year marriage?
He's my lifetime.
He's my whole, entire memory.
I don't know anything else.
I've never been on my own.
I'm not as brave as you two.
Call me.
How do you now plead to count one...
...the charge of securities fraud,
...guilty or not guilty?
Guilty.
How do you plead to count two...
...the charge of
investment advisory fraud,
...guilty or not guilty?
Guilty.
How do you now plead to count three...
...the charge of mail fraud?
...guilty or not guilty?
Guilty.
- How do you now plead to count four?
- Guilty.
- How do you now plead to count five?
- How do you now plead to count six?
- Guilty.
- How do you now plead to count seven?
- How do you now plead to count eight?
- Guilty.
- How do you now plead to count nine?
Guilty.
As Mr. Madoff has pled guilty,
...he is no longer entitled
to the presumption of innocence.
In light of his age,
he has incentive to flee.
He has the means to flee...
...and thus,
bail is revoked
...and the defendant is remanded.
Your Honor, would Your Honor
consider, respectfully,
...a stay so that we might appeal...
Your request for a stay is denied.
Mr. Madoff,
I will see you at sentencing.
- Sorry, Bernie.
- We are adjourned.
If you are visiting an inmate...
...in the maximum security wing,
...form a single-file line to your right.
Stop here.
Keys.
Turn around.
Open your legs.
In the cell next to me, they got this terrorist.
Some sheikh.
I can't remember his name.
But that's my neighbor.
Go figure.
I don't understand...
...why they put you in maximum security.
Did you finish packing up the apartment?
There's not much left to pack.
They're taking everything.
They even said to me,
"We're gonna need your
underwear and nightgowns."
- Who said that?
- US Marshals.
What would they want your underwear for?
They're gonna sell it.
They're gonna auction it off.
It's unbelievable.
Nothing is off-limits to these people.
I don't even like to think about it.
It's so spooky.
Have you spoken to the boys?
No one speaks to me...
...except my sister.
Joan even offered to let me
come stay with her in Boca.
- Well, she's your sister.
- Yeah, I know,
...but considering she and Bob
lost everything they had...
It was all with you.
I mean, it meant a lot to me.
Yeah, that was unfortunate.
That's why I was hoping
to have those few extra days...
...to make sure everyone was taken care of.
I just feel like such a
total putz.
I... I mean,
when you don't know what's going on,
...you don't even know what to say.
I mean, how am I supposed to
explain the Cohmad withdrawals?
You asked me to transfer money...
...from one account to another.
I do it and a few hours later,
...you tell me it's all a Ponzi scheme.
All these questions...
...and I don't
have any answers, Bernie.
Even if you had told me,
I'm not sure I
would've turned you in.
I don't know what that says about me.
That's the tragedy of it.
Mr. Madoff, are you scared
you're gonna lose your home?
Mr. Madoff, what do you have
to say to all of the people...
- Please go away.
- What the hell is wrong with you?!
- Please leave us alone.
- Can you put the camera down?
Do you feel guilty?
Do you feel remorseful?
You feeling like you're scared?
Do you feel any responsibility?
What the hell is wrong with you?!
What kind of person chases a family?
You don't have any right to touch my personal...
- I could sue you for shoving me.
- Oh, fuck you! Get in line.
Do you enjoy this?
Do you enjoy...
I don't get it, Mark.
- I don't get it.
- What's there to get?
Your first instinct was to abandon us.
I don't get that.
- I was waiting for you here...
- You left his stroller...
...in the middle of the street, Mark.
- It was on the sidewalk.
- It doesn't matter.
You just left me to deal with everything.
Do you understand how unfair that is?
This is about me.
They want me.
- This isn't about you.
- No, this is about all of us.
I... I am sick and tired of
you acting like it's not.
- You know...
- So what do you want, Steph? You want a divorce?
Just some acknowledgement.
Financial swindler Bernie
Madoff is awaiting sentencing
...at the Manhattan Correctional Facility
as investigators dig in...
...to see if those who were closest to Madoff...
Great.
This is unbelievable.
What has been called
the largest Ponzi scheme ever.
As we know, Bernie Madoff
has continued to maintain
...that he and only he
perpetuated this crime.
But it's clear the money trail is not real.
Every day, Mark sends you articles,
...things he's read,
things that pissed him off.
It's not fair.
It's not fair to you
and it's not fair to me.
I agree.
He's stuck.
He keeps going in circles reading blog after blog.
It's unhealthy.
But what do you want me to do, Catherine?
Create a little distance.
Well, that'd be easier if he wasn't
the only family member I have left.
Mark and Andrew Madoff's attorneys...
...say they are guilty of no crimes,
...but authorities and victims are
having trouble swallowing...
Andrew fucking Madoff.
How have you been, Reed?
Well, after your father fucked us all over,
...things have been
fucking fantastic.
Yeah, lots of job interviews.
No one willing to hire me, of course.
Working at BLM for seven years,
I guess I'm tainted.
Well, I know it's been tough on all of us,
...but you're a solid trader.
You'll find a job in no time.
Yeah, I get a lot of questions.
Yeah, especially about you, you and Mark.
"So the sons knew, right?"
"They were in on it.
They had to be, right?"
Reed, when I found out,
it was like my head exploded.
- I just...
- Shh, you hear that?
- What?
- It's the world's tiniest violin...
...playing the world's saddest fucking song.
I understand you're upset...
Yeah, well, how about making it right?
'Cause I was looking at a $450,000 bonus.
A lot of traders were owed bonuses, Reed.
You weren't the only one.
We all got screwed.
I thought you were all about family.
Well, what the fuck am I?
Am I not family, Andy?
Come on, where's the fucking money?
What'd you do with the money?
We all know you stole it.
Of course you took it.
You're a criminal!
I got fucked over, too!
By my own father!
My own father fucked me over!
Yeah, is that your whore?
I see you, whore!
- Hey! You...
- Hey!
Hey!
Stop it!
Andy, get in the car.
Hey!
Jesus, get in the car.
Jesus.
- Asshole. Hey!
- Here's your fucking latke,
- ...knish or whatever, you fuck.
- Hey!
Fuck you!
I know you're in on it!
Ugh.
The question is where did all the money go?
Irving Picard, the court-appointed trustee,
...the liquidator,
...is searching for the billions
that disappeared...
...and trying to recover as much as possible...
...from Madoff's remaining assets.
Of all the people that should've known,
...his brother and his sons,
...who worked under the same roof with him,
...should've known.
- One would think so, yes.
- Did they know?
My belief is, yes, they knew.
Clearly, they would have to
have known what was going on
- given their own personal transactions...
- Oh, we should've known?
We worked for market making.
He worked for IA.
- How would we have known?
- If they turn out to be untouchable,
...criminally, do you intend
to bankrupt them civilly?
Whether or not they have a criminal problem,
...we will pursue them
as far as we can pursue them.
And if that leads to
bankrupting them,
...then that's what will happen.
The man sitting in this courtroom robbed me.
He discarded me like roadkill.
What can we possibly say good
about Madoff...
...when he sank so low...
...as to steal from Elie Wiesel...
...as if Wiesel
hasn't already suffered enough in his lifetime.
My wife and I
are not millionaires.
We worked hard for all our lives...
...and he took our entire life savings.
Mr. Madoff not only defrauded
thousands of investors,
...he mastered the art of
manipulating our government.
The money Madoff stole from my family...
...had been set aside
to take care of my brother...
...because he's gonna need medical
assistance for the rest of his life.
If he's attempting to protect his family,
...he should not be given the opportunity...
...because we, his victims,
...did not have the same opportunity...
...to protect our families.
You have left your family with a legacy of shame.
You have a marriage made in hell,
...and that is where you are going to return.
I only hope his prison sentence is long enough...
...that his jail cell becomes his coffin.
May God spare you no mercy.
I am responsible...
...for a great deal of suffering and pain.
I understand that.
I live in a tormented state...
...now knowing of all the pain and suffering...
...that I have created.
That's something I will live with...
...for the rest of my life.
People have accused me of being silent...
...and not being sympathetic.
That is not true.
I apologize to my victims.
I will turn and face you.
I'm sorry.
I know that doesn't help.
Your Honor,
...thank you for listening.
The message must be sent...
...that Mr. Madoff's crimes...
...were extraordinarily evil.
This kind of irresponsible
manipulation of the system...
...takes a staggering human toll.
Mr. Madoff will get what he deserves...
...and will be punished...
...according to
his moral culpabilities.
Mr. Madoff,
please stand.
It is the judgment of this court...
...that the defendant,
Bernard L. Madoff,
...shall be and hereby is sentenced...
...to a term of imprisonment
of 150 years.
- What about our money, Bernie?!
- Yes!
Where's our money?!
As a technical matter,
...the sentence must be expressed in months.
150 years is equivalent...
...to 1,800 months.
We are adjourned.
We're standing outside of the
Federal Correctional Complex...
...in Butner, North Carolina,
...where Bernie Madoff just arrived
minutes ago.
We saw Mr. Madoff arrive on a bus...
...with a group of other inmates...
...where he will serve his
150-year prison sentence.
Officials have said he will
be watched carefully...
...to ensure he is not a danger to himself...
...as he faces the long years ahead.
Hmm.
Visiting hours at the prison are very liberal,
...and people close to the
Madoffs say his wife Ruth...
...may well move to North Carolina
to be close to her husband.
Oh, fuck you, you asshole.
I'm in Florida.
Very much in love...
...just like Bonnie was to Clyde, Charlie.
Bonnie robbed banks.
Bonnie killed people.
- And I'm Bonnie?
- by going to our blog
"The World Newser"
at abcnews.com.
How am I Bonnie?
Bonnie was a killer.
Bonnie killed people.
And I'm Bonnie?
For 16 years, I kept this secret...
...from my wife, from my brother,
...my sons.
How I was able to do that...
...and maintain any degree of sanity,
...well, that... that worries
me when I think about it.
You already mentioned that.
Yeah, I did.
But while we're on the subject,
...you say you wanted to protect your family.
Right.
But just an example,
...what would have happened...
...if at some point before the crisis of '08,
...you'd been hit by a bus,
you'd drop dead?
Mark and Andrew would've become the owners...
...of a firm that was still
in the middle...
...of perpetrating the biggest
Ponzi scheme in history.
Except the advisory was a
completely separate business,
...one in which they had no involvement, so...
But with you dead...
...and Frank probably willing...
...to swear to anything to save himself,
...seems to me the odds are...
...that as owners
as lifelong executives,
...they'd have gone to jail.
Your sons would be sitting there where you are.
No, well, I protected them.
You couldn't have protected
them if you were dead, Bernie.
So who would've been held responsible?
I would've been.
They would've been, Bernie.
They would've been held responsible,
...which means
one of two things is true.
Either they actually were guilty...
...and accepted the risks...
...or you were willing to let your sons
go to jail...
...for the crime you committed.
Which is it, Bernie?
I do like jousting with you.
I'm not jousting with you, Bernie.
- Yeah, well...
- I'm not jousting with you.
It seems to me like...
...like you're
refusing...
...to recognize
that hazard...
...you created for your family.
Not just the day you were arrested,
...but the hazard that they lived under,
...unknowing, for,
well, however long...
...you were operating this fraud.
Eventually, they would be exonerated.
- Period.
- How could you have been so certain of that,
...that you were willing to risk it?
Because they were never involved, ever,
...and there's no way it's ever
gonna be proven otherwise.
So it doesn't matter.
It's a terrible thing that they're going through,
...but they never would have been convicted...
...because they couldn't be convicted.
Because they didn't do anything.
Neither did my wife.
Nothing.
Zero.
- But you know what you've done...
- I know what I've done.
- Has shattered your family.
- I take full responsibility for that...
...and it'll... it'll
kill me for the rest of my life.
But...
Over the course of the summer and fall of 2009,
...the government auctioned off Madoff's property.
The beach house in Montauk...
$9 million.
The penthouse in Manhattan...
$8 million.
The Palm Beach house...
...available for $7.25 million.
The Mercedes-Benz station wagon,
yachts and power boats,
Mets jacket, a hodgepodge of personal items...
By the fall of 2009,
Picard had separately collected...
...roughly 1.5 billion...
...from the firm's brokerage and bank accounts,
...asset sales,
and a few out-of-court settlements.
We filed suit against Ruth Madoff...
...for 44 million.
We have filed a clawback suit...
...against Mark and Andrew Madoff...
...for the return of $127.5 million.
You can be in charge of the castle.
You can be in charge of the dresses.
- I get the dresses, right?
- Isn't that wig hysterical?
That's great.
Could you watch her for a minute?
Mark, any time we try...
...to move on with our life,
Bernie just finds a way to drag us back down.
- I'm sick of it.
- I'm sorry.
I tell you, you get angry.
I don't tell you, you get angry.
What am I supposed to do?
I don't know. It's just...
Oh, what the fuck
is wrong with this guy?
Suing our four-year-old daughter?
- It's insane.
- I know, I'm sorry.
I just... I hate that every time
I start to feel normal again,
something bad happens.
Have you
checked your text messages?
No.
Oh, my God, he's so cute.
I love you.
I love you, too.
Bye.
Hey, Marty,
I sent you the article.
Did you get it?
Anyway, please
give me a call back.
Hey, man, it's me.
What, are you away or something,
'cause I called you earlier
today and you didn't answer.
I left a message for Marty and
he's not there either.
Like, nobody ever seems to be around.
Everybody's out of town or something.
I'm leaving you another message.
I know I keep leaving
you messages, Andrew.
I can't even reach Stephanie.
I can't reach anybody!
I'm seriously gonna lose it.
I really am.
I'm, like, trapped in here.
Guess what.
It's me again.
I don't know if you're away with Cath...
...are you away with Catherine?
I mean, where are you guys, anyway?
Have you gone fishing?
It's just, like,
ever since she's been in your life,
I can't fucking reach you anymore.
I can't ever talk to you.
You're just, like, always fucking on some holiday!
Okay, ahem,
I just left you, like,
...a 20-minute message and I got cut off.
Andy, Marty,
I don't even know who I'm leaving messages for.
I'm just leaving messages now,
you know what I mean?
We're supposed to just sit
around and, like, you know,
...with our dicks in our hands,
doing nothing?
You know, I've been at this for two years.
Two years.
Two years!
I can't keep going on this way!
I have to make a statement.
I gotta make a
big statement!
I can't go on like this.
We're not here. Leave a message.
Mark, are you there?
Mark, pick up.
Your call has been forwarded...
...to an automatic voice message system.
At the tone,
please record your message.
Mark, I just
tried the house.
Uh... uh, call me.
Come in.
Mom.
What's wrong?
I just got these messages from Mark.
Uh, I tried calling the house,
...but he's...
he's not picking up.
All right, yeah, I just... I just pulled up.
I'm going inside.
I'll call you back.
All right.
Mark?
Hey!
Hey, Nicky.
What are you doing, huh?
Wanna come with Papa?
We're gonna go outside.
You wanna go outs...
Okay, uh.
Grouper!
Gotta get your blanky.
Grouper, come back.
Hey, Nicky, with Papa
we're gonna play peek-a-boo.
Grouper, come! Grouper!
Grouper! Grouper, come!
Come on, that's a good boy.
That's a good boy.
Look at...
Grouper, good.
We're just gonna go outside.
Hello?
It's Marty.
Mark's dead.
Stephanie!
- He... he hung himself.
- He's dead.
Has anybody called my mother?
I have to call my mother.
Andy?
It's so good to hear your voice, sweetheart.
I wrote Bernie a letter...
...a week
after Mark killed himself.
And I never sent it to him...
...because they monitor his mail...
...and I thought they would never, ever...
...give him a letter like this.
Well, here, you can say it on TV.
He's probably watching.
Well, what I wrote to him was,
"Bernie,
while I will not..."
"...send you pictures of your grandchildren,"
"...there is one picture I do want you to see."
"That last picture of your son Mark."
"You owe it
to his widow,"
"...his children,
his brother, his mother."
"So, here is what I wish for you, Bernie."
"Every time you sit down to eat,"
"...as you pick up your plastic fork,"
"I want you to see your son's corpse"
"...hanging from the rafter
directly over your table"
"...right on front of you, Bernie,"
"...so at every meal,
you see your son Mark..."
"...his white sweat socks
are swaying..."
"...ever so gently at your eye level..."
"...immediately above your food dish."
"And as you look up, Bernie,"
"...you see..."
"...you see your firstborn son hanging there,"
"...his head at a
left leaning angle..."
"...looking down at you,"
"...asking how could you do that to your son..."
"...who up until two years
before his death..."
"...had given you
the greatest gift..."
"...his unconditional love
for his father."
Well, I hope he heard that.
- I hope he heard that.
- Well, he gets free television,
...so why shouldn't he hear it?
Why isn't he in a hole
where he belongs?
He says that he is happier in prison...
- ...than he was before.
- Free meals!
- He feels safe in prison.
- His victims...
...are eating their dinner
out of cat food cans.
Then he says, "The average person
thinks I robbed widows and orphans."
"I made wealthy people wealthier."
That is not true.
Mark... he wrote a note.
The note said,
"Bernie,
this is what happens..."
"...when you destroy your sons..."
- "...by your life of deceit."
- Mm-hmm.
- "Fuck you, Bernie."
- That was Mark's suicide note.
- Right.
I can't keep coming here.
I want a relationship with Andy...
...and he won't see me if I keep coming here.
I can't have it both ways.
No, I understand.
And I can't talk to you anymore.
You can't write to me or call me.
It'll be too hard.
Ruth, all I want is what's best...
...for you and for the boys.
Boy, Bernie.
Boy.
You were my lifeguard.
I thought you were gonna protect me forever.
Best job I ever had.
I never had to save anybody.
I don't know if it will ever...
...be any different than it feels now.
I don't think after losing a child...
...things
ever get better.
I don't see much of a future for me.
And I don't really care if I have one.
The future's hard.
Yeah, I was sorry to see that
"People Magazine..."
...used that photo of
you and Mark when he was a boy.
I can never forgive you, Bernie.
And yet I'm not angry at you.
I don't know why.
It's a combination of feeling numb...
...and it seeming fruitless.
I don't remember how much
I got paid as a lifeguard,
...but it was never about the money.
In 2013,
I invited Andrew to speak at a writing seminar
I conducted at Princeton...
...under the general theme of
writing about con artists.
Andy had just started chemotherapy...
...for the reoccurrence of lymphoma.
The topic I asked him to
think about for the class...
...was how the media had
covered his father's case...
...and how that affected his life.
I've always wondered,
...why didn't you go on TV and state your case?
Why didn't you defend yourself?
Well, one of the reasons
I've always felt
uncomfortable...
...about the prospect of
going on TV and telling my story...
...is that I don't know if I'm
that sympathetic a character.
And at the end of the day,
I lived a life of great
wealth and privilege.
I traveled the world.
I wanted for nothing.
All of that was subsidized...
...by my father's victims.
It's hard to, um,
tell our story...
Mark's, my mother's, myself...
...when there are so many other stories.
My brother killed himself.
My mother lost
the only man she ever loved,
...turned out to be a complete fraud.
But, you know, there were just three of us.
There are
thousands of victims.
And, uh...
Any other questions?
Yes.
The father-son relationship...
...is such an important factor in anyone's life.
There must be some part of that
relationship with your father...
...that still exists.
Even after all this,
...can you see some point
where you could visit him...
...or talk to him again?
My father is dead to me.
On September 3rd, 2014,
...Andrew Madoff died...
...from mantle cell lymphoma.
Hi, this is Ruth.
Leave a message after the tone.
Hi, Ruth, I just wanted to...
I know I,
said I wouldn't call, but I just, um...
...um, okay.
Hi, this is Ruth.
Leave a message after the tone.
We're sorry.
You have reached a number
that is no longer in service.
If you feel that you have reached
this recording in error,
...please check the number and...
Hey, I was online today...
...and I'm reading some of
the old coverage of me...
...and I came across this article.
Frankly, it was just ridiculous.
What was the article?
The "New York Times" interviewed
this guy, a forensic psychologist...
...who worked on the Ted Bundy case.
And this guy, Joe Blow,
...whom I've never met,
never talked to...
...don't know from Adam, never
seen in my whole entire life...
...was going on and on
about the similarities...
...between Ted Bundy and myself.
Ah, I can see how that comparison
would be troubling, but...
Well, there is no comparison.
I mean, how can you compare me to someone...
...who decapitated women and
kept their heads as mementos?
I mean, that's the behavior of a
truly, truly evil human being.
I mean, what comparison is there,
ever, possibly in that?
And yet the "New York Times,"
...the newspaper of record,
...all the news that's fit to print...
...never had anyone say this is a
preposterous piece of writing,
...especially for the business section.
Well, why do you think they made that comparison?
- You know, when I turned myself in...
- Your sons turned you in.
No, no, but I turned myself in.
It was a matter of a few days,
so I was gonna do it.
So anyway, when I turned myself in...
...it was the height of the whole
anti-Wall Street hysteria...
...and they needed a villain,
they needed a face...
...for the whole mess they created.
That face became me,
so that's...
I don't know, I just...
I don't even wanna think about it.
Think about what?
Well, he killed people,
innocent people.
And in my case,
I told people, everyone,
"Don't put more than half your money with me."
"You never know.
Who the hell knows?"
"I mean, one day,
I could just go crazy."
But the reality is people are greedy.
Hmm, the reality is that
not even your warning was true...
...and you took their money anyway.
Let me ask you a question.
Do you think I'm a sociopath?